<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ProposalDocument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <preliminarySection>
    <titlePage>
      <title />
      <author />
      <supervisors>
        <string> Laurence Beder </string>
      </supervisors>
      <titleParagragh1>requirements for the degree of Master of Management in the field of   Digital Business </titleParagragh1>
      <titleParagraph2 />
      <submissionDate>Johannesburg, August 2021</submissionDate>
    </titlePage>
    <declarationPage>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DECLARATION</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>I, Ahmed Ismail Kajee, declare that this research report is my own work except  as indicated in the references and acknowledgements. It is submitted in partial  fulfilment of the requirements for the degree of Master of Management in the field  of Digital Business at the University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg. It has  not been submitted before for any degree or examination in this or any other  university. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Name:  Ahmed Ismail Kajee  Signature:   Signed at: Johannesburg, South Africa……………………………….  rd On the 23 ……………….. day of August…………………………. 2021 </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
      <pageNumber>0</pageNumber>
    </declarationPage>
    <acknowledgementPage>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This work would not have been possible without the inspiration and motivation I  received from my classmates, many of whom provided me with the tools and  advice that I needed throughout this research. Thanks is also due to my employer  Nedbank, who gave me the funding and the flexibility to embark on this masters  journey. A special word of appreciation for my supervisor, Laurence Beder, who  guided this work through his ongoing communication, and generously sharing his </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>knowledge and insights.   Finally, a sincere thanks to the participants and industry professionals who </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>contributed to this research either formally via interviews, or by being sounding  boards for my ideas. Co-creating this report with them has been a very rewarding  learning experience.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
      <pageNumber>0</pageNumber>
    </acknowledgementPage>
    <listOfContentsPage>
      <table>
        <string>TABLE OF CONTENTS</string>
        <string>ABSTRACT ..................................................................................... ii  DECLARATION .............................................................................. iii  DEDICATION ................................................................................. iv  ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS ................................................................ v </string>
        <string>LIST OF TABLES ............................................................................ x  LIST OF FIGURES ......................................................................... xi  CHAPTER 1. INTRODUCTION .................................................... 13  </string>
      </table>
    </listOfContentsPage>
    <listOfFiguresPage>
      <figures>
        <string>LIST OF FIGURES</string>
        <string>Figure 1: Internet Penetration in SA (Source: Statista) .................................... 14  Figure 2: Time spent on Internet in South Africa (Source: Kemp, S. 2019a) .... 14  Figure 3: Social Media Advertising Profile (Source: Kemp, S. 2019a) ............. 15  Figure 4: Social Media Usage Breakdown SA (Source: Kemp, S. 2019a) ....... 15  Figure 5: SA Influencer and Reach Volumes (Source: Humanz, 2020) ........... 17 </string>
        <string>Figure 6: Influencer Marketing Objectives Breakdown (Source: Talkwater, 2019)  ......................................................................................................................... 18  Figure 7: Influencer Marketing Measurement (Source: Rakuten, 2019) ........... 20 </string>
        <string>Figure 8: Global Influencer Marketing Growth (Source: IMH, 2020) ................. 28  Figure 9: Influencer Marketing Platforms (Source: IMH, 2020) ........................ 29  Figure 10: Influencer Categories (Source: Campbell and Farrell, 2020) .......... 30 </string>
        <string>Figure 11: Influencer Usage Ratio (Source: IMH, 2020) .................................. 31  Figure 12: DIM within Paid, Owned and Earned Marketing Channels (Source:  Authors own, adapted from Stephen and Galak, 2012) ................................... 33  Figure 13: DIM SA Engagement Rates (Source: Humanz, 2020) .................... 37 </string>
        <string>Figure 14: 5 A's of Marketing (Source: Kotler et al, 2017) ................................ 41  Figure 15: PAR / BAR Marketing Measurement Models (Source: Kotler et al,  </string>
        <string>Figure 18: Influencer Marketing Best Practices Conceptual Framework (Source:  Authors Own) ................................................................................................... 53 </string>
        <string>Figure 20: High Level Participant and Interview Data ...................................... 69  Figure 21: Data Analysis Examples ................................................................. 70  Figure 22: Influencers Impact on Consumers (Source: Authors own) .............. 79  Figure 23: Relationship between Influencer Authenticity and Engagement </string>
        <string>(Source: Authors own) ..................................................................................... 85  Figure 24: DIM Cross Functional Marketing Value Drivers (Source: Authors own)</string>
        <string> ......................................................................................................................... 87  Figure 25: Influencer Marketing Maturity Stages (Source: Authors own) ......... 89 </string>
        <string>Figure 26: Influencer Selection Categories (Source: Authors own) ................ 101  Figure 27: Influencer Audience Composition (Source: Authors own) ............. 103  Figure 28: Influencer Selection Consideration Factors (Source: Authors own)</string>
        <string> ....................................................................................................................... 105  Figure 29: Creative Control in DIM (Source: Authors own) ............................ 108 </string>
        <string>Figure 30: DIM Value within Marketing Stages (Source: Authors own) .......... 113  Figure 31: Risk Framework for DIM (Source: Authors own) ........................... 117 </string>
      </figures>
    </listOfFiguresPage>
    <listOfTablesPage>
      <table>
        <string>LIST OF TABLES</string>
        <string>Table 1: Influencer Marketing Types (Adapted from Campbell and Farrell, 2020)  ......................................................................................................................... 30  Table 2: Influencer Research Categories and Questions ................................. 55 </string>
        <string>Table 3: Profile of Research Participants ......................................................... 62  x </string>
      </table>
    </listOfTablesPage>
    <abstractPage>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>ABSTRACT</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This research report highlights the growth of Digital Influencer marketing  on  social media, and how consumers interaction and engagement with brands are  changing as a result. Through qualitative research with 17 Digital Influencer  experts and practitioners in South Africa from various marketing disciplines, this  study sheds light on best practices for this emerging marketing field.   In South Africa, consumer attention and media consumption are increasingly </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>becoming digitally centric, and the use of online channels for marketing continues  to grow exponentially. This has implications for brand building, advertising, and  marketing management. This research reports on how the traditional marketing  and consumer behaviour paradigms have shifted from uni-directional static  advertising, towards bi-directional digital engagement using Digital Influencer  Marketing (DIM). As a growing field, the research found that although DIM as a  marketing tactic is increasingly effective in meeting business objectives in  modern day digital marketing environments, there is a lack of knowledge and  shared best practices amongst marketing practitioners.  The research finds that despite DIM growing and being strategically important in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>all the marketing environments that have been researched, most organisations  are conducting DIM on a “best-effort” basis with limited cross functional co- ordination or strategic planning. Due to a lack of knowledge about the field, there </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>is also relatively little action being taken by organisations to meet the growing  demand by putting in place the requisite skills and capabilities to better manage  influencer marketing initiatives. Aspects highlighted in this research such as </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer Performance, Payment, Brand Safety, Campaign Management,  Creative Control, Organisational Capabilities, and Risks associated with DIM are  discussed and reported on, providing marketing practitioners with practical  insights into this emerging marketing field.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>A key recommendation emanating out of this research is that DIM is not the  responsibility of any specific marketing function, for it to be successful, cross- functional expertise, integration, and management is required.  ii </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
      <pageNumber>0</pageNumber>
    </abstractPage>
  </preliminarySection>
  <contentSection>
    <chapterOne>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>CHAPTER 1. INTRODUCTION</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>discussed, there is an increasingly larger share of consumer attention shifting  towards social media platforms, and in particular, to Influencer Marketing. This  research is therefore significant in that it will support marketers to better  understand how to be more successful on social media by leveraging and  managing influencers for various marketing and commercial purposes.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>history of civilisation. This exponential growth across digital platforms and  services shows no signs of abaiting. According to Statista (July, 2020) South  Africa’s internet penetration is reportedly between 56,3% - 62%, with 36,54 million  active internet users as at January 2020, of whom 22 million are active Social </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>media users. These numbers are forecasted to grow in the coming decade as  can be seen in Figure 1  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>13</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Recent studies by WeAreSocial (Hootsuite,2020) show that as of July 2020, more  than 50% of the worlds population was active on Social Media, having grown to  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>last year (2019), with the global average being 6h42 min. In South Africa, WeAreSocial (January, 2020) show that new Social Media users grew by 19%, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>or 3,5 million additional users in the 9 months between April 2019 and January  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>50% more than the global average. A third of this time (3h10min) is spent on Social Media, and roughly 60% of these users are between 18-34 years old. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>14</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Instagram, and Twitter are amongst the top 10 visited platforms with 98% of  active social media users accessing these from mobile devices. Reports further  show that Social media platforms such as Youtube, Facebook, and Instagram  have the highest penetration rate of internet users ranging between 61% to 87%, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with other smaller (by size) Social platforms such as Twitter, LinkedIn, Snapchat,  TikTok etc having significant penetration. The top 3 as is noted in Figure 4 are  Watsapp, YouTube, and Facebook  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The significance of these numbers show that the internet, and social media  specifically, is growing rapidly. This growth in and of itself may at first glance </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>15</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>appear to be of limited significance for strategic marketing as these platforms  could merely be seen as additional consumer reach channels. When considered </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>competition for consumer attention is intensifying, and that Social media  platforms are attracting an increasingly larger share of consumers time. This  trend continues to signal the migration of customer attention away from traditional  media (i.e. TV, Radio, Newspapers etc) to Digital media. This trend has profound  implications for marketers and advertisers. Media, marketing and advertising  values chains are being reconfigured, and businesses and their marketers need  to better understand how to compete for, reach, and attract consumers attention </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>in this Digital driven world. This involves understanding consumers online  preferences, habits, behaviours, and interests. Businesses need to be able to  utilise emerging digital marketing tactics effectively to reach consumers.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>16</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the right influencers, and finding creative ways to work with influencers were  identified as the top 3 challenges. Their research identified that authenticity in  brand marketing was an important component of driving value through  influencers, and that longer term relationships with influencers were likely to start  forming. Also, that much of the work being done in influencer marketing happens  in a manual manner bringing about automation and measurement challenges.  With only 31,5% of marketers having an official influencer marketing program in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>place, they see this area representing opportunities into the future. Although  influencers can be used to achieve multiple marketing objectives, an  overwhelming majority of respondents (65,8%) as can be seen in Figure 6 chose </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Brand visibility as key objectives for influencer marketing. This was followed by  Leads / Sales (16,9%), Creative Campaigns (10,4%), Customer Loyalty (4,2%),  and Other objectives (2,7%).  Reasons for this selection are not provided,  therefore questions as to why these objectives are selected remain.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>17</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relationships between social media and influencer marketing as it relates to  marketing and consumer behaviour at a specific digital channel level.  In terms of content, Video is preferred, followed by images and then written </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>content. This has implications for the creation or co-creation of the branded  content between brands and influencers. Sharing of influencer content amongst  consumers is growing, Word-of-Mouth marketing therefore remains a core  component Social media marketing (Chen, Z. and Yuan, M. 2020). Referrals by </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>friends and family or brand product giveaways play a major role in online  consumer behaviour. Interestingly, the research overwhelmingly shows that less  than 1% of consumers have not discovered a brand via influencers, and that 87%  of consumers were inspired to make a purchase based on influencer content. The </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>18</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>frequency of these brand and product discovery behaviours with 65% of  consumers doing so weekly and 24% doing so daily makes Influencer marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Not only does it support brand and product discovery, but 80% of consumers  surveyed were reportedly comfortable with clicking through on influencer content  to make purchases, making it a sales tool as well. In the US for instance, 80% of  consumers surveyed had actually clicked through and made a purchase after  seeing influencer sponsored posts and links.   Since Social media platforms transcend borders, consumers are increasingly </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>following international influencers. This means that brands could increasingly use  influencers from outside their countries to market to their local consumers.  Conversely, it also means that consumers perceptions and competition is  increasingly being shaped on the global stage.  Over 49% of consumers said that Influencer Marketing offers them entertainment, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and a further 49% found information that influencers shared useful content, with  authenticity playing a key role. Consumers are reportedly prone to following  recommendations of influencers that align to their values, ethics, and passion,  and who have “good taste”. In contrast to traditional branded advertising which  struggles to break through the clutter, this kind of engagement is highly sought  after by marketers looking to gain product or brand awareness.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Brands can therefore get considerable advertising value from influencer who are  deemed authenthic, trustworthy, honest and ethical. However, given that  Influencers share branded content through sponsored posts or product reviews  for which they get paid, 34% of consumers reportedly do not trust sponsored </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>content. This opens up many questions regarding selecting influencers, and  ethical considerations of disclosing sponsorships to maintain influencer  credibility. Stubb et al’s research (2019) provides insights into ways of increasing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>sponsored content affectiveness, this will be discussed later in this report. The  IMH (2020) however showed that a low 14% of influencers comply with disclosure  requirements, making this a risk for brands. Also that 78% of marketers produced  and managed influencer marketing in-house, with the remainder outsourced to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>19</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>agencies. This means that marketers need to manage more influencers into the  future, and to develop influencer marketing skills and capabilities.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketers tracking Brand Reach, Awareness, Direct Sales, Online Traffic and  Indirect sales. Challenges in Influencer fraud however represents a key issue with  68% of IMH (2020) respondents having been victims of influencer fraud. This  includes fake and inactive followers and bots that can skew influencer rating and  results. This is estimated in South Africa to be approximately 18% on both  Instagram and Twitter (HumanAi, 2020).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Tracking performance and paying influencers go hand in hand, this works  according to deliverables required from influencers as well as results achieved.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>There are therefore various types of payment models depending on how  infuencers are used. Some of these include position based payment, first click,  time-decay, equal credit, or last click – or a combination of these. There however  does not appear to be an industry standard with many marketers unsure of how  payment for influencers should work, and 54% reported that they “somewhat  understand” how marketing fees work for influencers. Figure 7 above shows the  different measurement approaches. What compounds this is that only a paltry  23% of influencers are open about how they get paid, with many marketers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>20</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>reporting that the influencers they work with don’t care about results. The  payment model is a key component of the working relationship between </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Creative power is yet another pitfall that has not been fully understood. Brands of  course need to ensure their reputations are protected, and that their brand tone  is maintained through content that is well thought out and not offensive. At the  same time, the authenticity of the influencer needs to be upheld. This is a fine  balancing act that is far from being resolved, with the power relationships yet to  be established. According to the Rakuten report, 61% of marketers surveyed said  that influencers were open to creative content suggestions, but that only 40% are </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>open to best practices, whereas 18% said that influencers hold all the creative  power.    To understand this emerging marketing tactic better, best practices are needed </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>in influencer skills, measurement, payment, creative, and risk management – to  mention a few. These will guide marketers to get the most out of this exciting field.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>century,  with different streams of marketing practice and theory emerging over  the decades. Starting with Print, Radio, and Television advertising, marketing  management has evolved to include Telemarketing, Customer Relationship  Marketing (CRM), Direct Marketing, Relationsip Marketing, Integrated Marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Communications (IMC). More recently, Digital Marketing has now become an  indispensable part of the marketing toolbox.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>21</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital Marketing as a growing field not only represents digital platforms where  consumers are engaged in digital media consumption, but they represent new </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>platforms. Some Marketing management theories have evolved to be applicable  in these contexts, such as Direct Marketing integrating Email Marketing into its  practices, there remain gaps within the marketing body of knowledge to  accommodate for the specificities of many areas within Digital Marketing. These  include but are not limited to Search Engine Optimisation, Social Media  Marketing, Mobile Marketing, Web Marketing, and Digital Media Advertising.  Digital Marketing definitions vary, but Stokes, R (2018)  state that the complete </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>scope of marketing can be practiced on the internet, and that Digital marketing  involves marketing in a digital world. Citing Cadell (2013), Digital is described as  a “participatory layer of all media that allows users to self-select their own  experiences and affords marketers the ability to bridge media, gain feedback, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>iterate their message and collect relationships”. This can include the use of  Search Engine Marketing (SEM), Search Engine Optimisation (SEO), Social  Media Marketing, and User Experience Management amongst other areas.  A gap however exists in understanding marketing best practices as it relates to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital Influencer Marketing. Campbell and Farell (2020) concur pointing out that  despite increasing growth in the use of influencer marketing tactics, that “little </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>strategic or academic insight exists that is specific to influencers”.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>neither are the mitigating techniques to identify and manage influencer fraud and  risks. Shifts are occurring in the use of influencers for brand awareness and  engagement, to include achieving direct and indirect sales, this means its impact  on businesses bottom lines can be more tangible. This makes influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>22</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing an important sales tool provided marketers can understand how to  leverage it more effectively.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>amongst marketers with no clearly defined industry standards. Whilst the  majority of influencer marketing is produced and managed in-house, little is said  about how this is done, or the management structures and departments that  support effective influencer marketing. The low levels of compliance from  influencers themselves in disclosing paid partnerships ought to receive  increased attention given the risk it represents to brands. Also, regulatory  standards requirements, and the ethical obligations of parties involved to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>disclose sponsorships or endorsements remain opaque.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>music, sports and other activities, and who are contracted in offline situations. It  should be kept in mind that offline celebrities consistently also use their digital  presence to leverage influence for brands, companies and their products.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>23</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>therefore warrants further research. This is supported by the historical evolution  of marketing, where in general, theory normally follows practice. Further evidence </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and platforms which now number 1300 globally (Campbell,C. Farrell, J R. 2020).  Traditional marketing agencies are also setting up new platforms focused  exclusively on Influencer Marketing, such as InfluenceO which was recently  launched in South  Africa by long standing agency Ogilvy and Mather  (Bizcommunity, August 2020). These market signals highlight the growth and  importance of influencer marketing.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>24  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
    </chapterOne>
    <chapterTwo>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>CHAPTER 2. LITERATURE REVIEW</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>specifically due to digital options.  In this chapter therefore, influencer marketing  is explored with an Integrated Marketing Communication (IMC) lense.  In terms of the marketing body of knowledge, Digital Influencer marketing has </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>many parallels with Word-of-Mouth marketing (WOM) which was originally  defined by Brooks (1957). Rosario et al (2020) point out that WOM has become  more relevant, and has been given new significance due to the internet. The  growth of internet usage - in particular social media, has given consumers the  ability to widely share their opinions and feedback on topics ranging from politics,  environment, and business, to brands and their products and services. This  phenomeonon is termed eWOM, or electronic word of mouth. According to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Rosario’s (2020) definition, eWOM is “consumer-generated, consumption-related  communication that employs digital tools and is directed primarily to other  consumers”. They point out that despite eWOM’s growing significance and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>consumers reliance on it for their buying decisions, “marketers are still struggling  to maximize the business value of eWOM”. Their research covered “consumer- generated content, electronic word of mouth, online review, online word of mouth,  social earned media, and user-generated content”, all of which have clear </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>parallels to Digital influencer marketing. They also identify 3 key consumers roles  being that of creating eWom, exposure to eWom, and evaluating eWom.  Importantly, they distinguish between the role of consumers who “send and  receive eWom”, and that of marketers who “amplifies and manages eWOM for  business results”. Thus similarities between Influencers who send and receve  eWOM can be identified. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>25</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>It could be argued that Digital Influencers are fast becoming the most dominant  form of eWOM given the proliferation of Social media. Rosario et al (2020) state </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>With the exception of Ranking, Reviews and Recommendations commonly  known as the 3 R’s (Park et al, 2007)  - which is a form of eWOM that drives  purchase behaviour and repurchase intention in online marketplaces and e- commerce platforms, this study views eWOM in the context of social media that  is driven by influencers through their content. This view fits well with Rosario et  al’s (2020) research into eWOM across 1050 research papers which found that  the common underpinning of eWOM theories and / or frameworks is their “focus </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>on influential consumers and their role in spreading information”.  These “influential consumers” are now simply  called influencers, and this </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>research thus from a marketing theory context explores the factors involved in  amplifying and managing eWOM. The research specifically looks at eWOM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>generated by and through Digital Influencers to achieve marketing and business  results.   With the emergence and growth of new communications environment, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>consumers have more channels to interact with brands, whether by sms, email,  online chat, or social media posts. As a result, the time delays from request to  responses between companies and their customers are also getting shorter.  The </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>growth of these digital communications channels bring with them a new marketing   environment, a digital one. Keller (2016) points out that this allows engagement  between consumers and brands to be very high on the one extreme through  online web and social media services with proactive consumers highly active in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>shaping brand perceptions through engaged online brand communities. On the  other extreme, engagement may be low or non existent with no online  communication services available, typically resulting in a brand not benefiting </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>from an online presence. Therefore, it can be understood that a strong online  presence necessitates high online engagement.   These online brand communities as Keller (2016) calls it, support companies “to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>drive short-term sales, they can offer promotions and other incentives through  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>26</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>tweets, texts, and targeted e-coupons. And to reinforce long-term brand loyalty,  they can form online brand communities through their own or third-party social </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>uses moving away from only brand engagement, to become more direct and  indirect sales related through promotions. Also, influencers operate on social  media and are external to the brand i.e. third party, therefore it can be surmised  that influencer marketing audiences fits exactly with Kellers (2016) description of  Online Brand Communities.  DIM as a marketing mechanism can support this  effectively as it provides brand awareness and reach, positive eWOM, sales  promotion support, and customer loyalty.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that brands and marketers need to take a much more active role in managing  their brands advertising online. Negative electronic word of mouth (WOM) can  impact on product sales and brand reputation (Chen and Yuan, 2020) and in  extreme cases, lead to severe financial losses – and overall company  reputational loss.   In recent times, there has been a spotlight on brand marketing on Social Media, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with Clicks for example experiencing backlash (Daily Maverick, September  2020). Although not an influencer driven campaign, it is clear that more attention </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>needs to be paid to the companies reputation when advertising online, via Social  Media specifically. Influencer Marketing according to Campbell and Farrell (2020)  is “the practice of compensating individuals for posting about a product or service  on social media”. It is a sub-set of Social media marketing, which itself is a sub-</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>27</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>set of Digital Marketing. There are part of the overall Marketing body of  knowledge.   They state that Influencer marketing is estimated to grow to $101 billion globally </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>10% of marketing budgets are allocated towards this. They also report that over  80% of marketers intend to set aside dedicated budgets for this medium.  Influencer marketing has been gaining popularity as an effective marketing tactic  that is being used for brand awareness and development, product marketing and  promotion, and increasingly to drive sales, with growing success. These global  figures are naturally estimations as Figure 8 indicates, they do however give us  a good idea of the scale and pace of growth of DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>There is also a growth in dedicated Influencer Marketing agencies with 380 new  influencer platforms and agencies in 2019 totalling 1120 (See Figure 9). Recently  for example, Ogilvy  - a global marketing agency giant, had recently launched </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>28</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>their “InfluencerO” platform in South Africa (Bizcommunity, August 2020).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencers into 5 types, these are listed in Table 1  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>29</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer Type Audience Description  Size  Nano (Newcomer)  0 – 10K Generally a niche influencer who is new to influencing and has a small following but  tend to have higher engagement rates as they are perceived to be highly authentic, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and accessible.  Micro (Rising Star) 10 - 100k  An influencer who has built a strong and growing following through either niche </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>expertise or lifestyle related content that offers value to their audience. Their also have  higher engagement rates.   Macro (Sweet Spot) 100k – An established influencer that has amassed a sizeable audience and is well regarded  1mil amongst their followers for the value of their content, their opinions, their tastes, or the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>quality of their interaction.   Mega (Everyday 1mil + An influencer who has “made-it” online with a large following making them an online  Celeb)  celebrity through the value they add, and also possibly breaking into offline influencing.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Celebrity(Rich&amp; 1mil +  A traditional celebrity such as a sports person or musician that already have a large  Famous)  offline fan base who also follow them on Social media, giving them online influencing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>capabilities.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>30</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>As can be seen, using Mega-influencers can have the same impact as offline  Celebrities endorsing brands. They are associated with Brand strategy </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>follower growth increases, perceived authenticity and influencer accessibility  tends to decline, leading to lower engagement rates. IMH (2020) report a growing  trend to include more micro-influencers for every macro-influencer. Figure 11  shows that in 2016 this ratio was 1 to 3, whereas in 2019 it changed to 1 to 10.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This opens up many considerations for brands who associate closely with  influencers, higher reach may come at the expense of lower engagement. Also,  with Mega and Macro influencers and their large reach and online celebrity status,  brand reputational risk can be a serious issue.  Influencers in the digital world  whose followers, fans or audiences are leveraged for marketing activities could  be relatively unknown outside of Social Media, but yet have the potential to cause  reputational harm to a brand. This is seen in the offline world from the cases of  Tiger Woods that impacted brands such as Tag Heur and Nike who reportedly </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>lost between $5 – 12 million as a result of his infidelity, and callous drunk driving  behaviour (Campbell and Farrell, 2020).   The National Broadcasting Standards Authority of South Africa (NABSA) </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>regulates traditional media, with the Advertising Standards Authority (ASA)  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>31</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>regulating the marketing fraternity conduct. Influencers blur the lines between  Media and Advertising. On the one hand, they offer brands reach and awareness, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>also provide conversion to sales via product recommendations, and affiliate  marketing. This makes it a powerful marketing and advertising mechanism.   A clear distinguishing factor for Digital Marketing, specifically Social Media </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing, is the public and real-time interactivity with masses of consumers at  scale. This means that executing and managing a Digital Influencer marketing  (DIM) campaign requires a marketing environment that actively monitors,  engages, and responds to consumers online.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital influencer marketing also straddles multiple functions within marketing  departments. Whilst there is a big digital social media component, it can also be  purchased as posts or tweets similar to traditional media blocks, or negotiated as  part of a sponsorship endorsement or public relations contract. 80% of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>respondents in the IMH (2020) said that influencer marketing was budgeted for  from PR departments. It is still however unclear at the moment whether this  should be under the purview of the media, advertising, brand management, public  relations, marketing communications, digital marketing, or other marketing  function.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communications as either Paid (eg. buying of advertising space on TV, Radio,  Billboard or Magazine), Owned (eg. Company Blog, Website, Social Media  Accounts, or Mobile Apps), or Earned (eg. Word of Mouth, PR Coverage etc).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>32</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The Paid, Owned and Earned distinction, whilst applicable to many other types  of marketing, does little to clarify Influencer Marketing. The influencer for example </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>advertising. Influencer content can also be integrated on company owned digital  platforms to engage customers, and they can clearly generate earned media in  the form of content sharing, recommendations, and referrals. Also, influencers  can play the role of a creative agency partner by developing content for  audiences, and managing the campaign and its engagement on behalf of the  brand. This places them at the intersection of these 3 different forms of marketing  communications as explained in Figure 12 below  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(Source: Authors own, adapted from Stephen and Galak, 2012)  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>33</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that the current marketing mix and IMC framework is inadequate in that it  “belies the paradigm shift that has occurred in consumers’ behaviour,  attitudes and use of media and, therefore, hardly does it justice”. They  therefore propose a reconceptualization of the traditional marketing mix </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>into an IMC2.0 to cater for Social media marketing, and its unique  capabilities to generate “viral marketing” communications – or in simpler  terms, shares, recommendations, and referral. This extends marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communications beyond paid media advertising.   The paradigm shift being referred to relate to people and societal changes </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>such as consumer behaviours and political views, technology changes  from analogue to digital, media changes from traditional communications  channels to internet driven media, information changes in the spread and  accessibility to knowledge, and changes in economy and business  represented by money flows. This shift is driven largely by digital  connectivity, applications, services, platforms, content and media that is  bi-directional. It traverses cultural, demographic, social, economic, and  geographic boundaries.   Changing business and consumer working and personal environments </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>has shaped new routines driven by online services, communities, media,  and social networks Jackson and Ahuja (2016). Online information and its </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>exploration has changed media habits and consumption patterns. Online  communities  by businesses and consumers now garner high levels of  engagement and quality participation that engender trust and loyalty.   Convenient mobile and other connected devices make access from </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>34</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>anywhere at anytime possible, resulting in contextually aware  communications becoming highly important. Bi-Directional </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>instantaneous with messaging and chat services enabled by the internet  and social platforms, this calls for new ways of developing and planning  marketing and communications initiatives.   Collectively, these digitally driven market forces are fundamentally </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>changing the way brands communicate to customers. New customer  routines, media consumption habits, online engagement trends, access to  information, and ubiquitous connectivity requires new ways of thinking.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketers as a result require new models of marketing and communication  st for the 21 century. Jackson and Ahuja (2016) identify Relationship  Marketing (RM), Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Co-</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Creation, Salesforce automation, and Digital Marketing as important  components of contemporary marketing.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Relationship Marketing focuses on brands investing in the brand- consumer relationship to move customers from engaged and involved to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>loyal. Engaged customers on Social media platforms could be those that  like posts or contents, whilst involved customers may be those who  regularly comment. Loyal customers are ones that share brand content, or  refer and recommend products online. The intent of CRM is to include </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>lifetime value of customers through creating social bonds as can be found  in peer-to-peer social networks and online brand communities. Financial  bonds such as purchases involve customer targeted promotions with  coupons, and structural bonds can include priviledged access to an online </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>platform. These are seen to lead to loyalty. Co-creation is also an  important aspect of contemporary marketing, allowing customers and  brands to interact freely in the exchange of product ideas and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>improvements. This can be enabled through digital via online  engagements on Social media platforms.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>35</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital influencer marketing as a tool can leverage RM, CRM and Co- creation. In terms of Salesforce automation, DIM opts instead to allow for </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>power is shifting to the digitally connected consumer. This therefore  warrants a shift to digitally powered marketing – or Digital Marketing.   Given the profileration of Online Web Communities which are increasingly </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>fragmented into sub-cultures, brands cannot assume to be able to use  traditional consumer segmentation any longer – it is too static and vertical  i.e. top down segmentation. Also, fragmentation of media into countless  options means that reach, messaging believability and source credibility  are under threat with increasingly lower advertising efficacy and  engagement rates. This means that the strategic marketing roles that  influencers play is to offer marketers improved customer segmentation </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>based on niche online communities. Jackson and Ahuja (2016) termed this  the “Customer Mix”, and propose that it should precede the development  of the marketing mix and messaging. This is because online communities  increasingly shape marketing strategy and communication plans. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencers closeness to the communities they create or participate in also  means that they can deliver more credible and relevant messaging that  has higher levels of authenticity and value to the consumer. This improves </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>advertising effectiveness and engagement rates.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>36</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Recent South African research conducted by Humanz (2020) shown in  being as high as 34,69% with influencers who have smaller audiences.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>These relatively high engagement rates represents a strong opportunity  for marketers to leverage DIM within their IMC strategies.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relationships between theconsumers of goods, services and experiences  and their suppliers”.   This is premised on their 4 P’s i.e. People, Personalities, Perceptions and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>st Participation and serves to highlight the nature of 21 century marketing.  In terms of People, this is encapsulated by empowered, digitally connected </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and internet savvy content creators and consumers, who rely on peer  reviews, searches and online communities for their decision making. This </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>makes managing online communications and reputation for brands an  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>37</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>instrumental component. From a personality perspective, Jackson and  Ahuja (2016) highlight the importance of specific customer targeting </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>recognise individuality and support personal expression is thus critical to  successful marketing.   Perception in the Digital age becomes more fluid, as digital platforms allow </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>brands to shape and reshape these more actively with consumers. Brands  can now test and execute different positionings and strategies, and allow  for different meanings to develop in the brand-customer relationship within  online digital communities.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Finally, regarding Participation, the Digital age allows for interactive, real- time, bi-directional communications between brands and customers. This  results in the ability of brands to move away from creating adverts to  developing shared experiences that consumers can participating in, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>making the interaction more rewarding for both parties.   Clear parallels can be drawn from this framework to the investigation into </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DIM with People being Influencer Audiences who represent different and  varied customer typologies in sometimes small numbers within online  communities, Personalities being  the Influencers themselves who create  and share content and act as conduits for brand and marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communication activities, Perceptions being the specific audience view  and outlook towards brands which inform the content marketing strategy  and activities online. Participation is highlighted by their level of  engagement and interactivity with influencer and brand content which </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>creates shared, relevant, and meaningful brand experiences for  consumers.   Though the frameworks of different authors may differ, Kotler et al (2017) </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>agree with this viewpoint and attribute changes directly to the rise of social  media. They encapsulate is as follows “In the digital economy, customers  are now facilitated and empowered to evaluate and even scrutinize any </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>38</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>company's brand-positioning promise. With this transparency (due to the  rise of social media) brands can no longer make false, unverifiable </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>there is essentially a community-driven consensus the positioning  amounts to nothing more than corporate posturing”.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>product promoter (i.e. Endorsement), or as an external marketing partner  or agency (i.e. Social Media manager).   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>values to ensure authenticity. Finally, their attitude and receptive to what  the brand is doing is important so that they are able to work together with  the brand to plan, execute and manage content campaigns by balancing  the needs of their audiences with those of the brand.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This according to them, entails horizontal web communities that is different  from vertical segmentation since customers are social connected to each  other. Communities therefore become the new segmentation, and Digital </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing, and by extension - Influencer marketing, requires an  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>39</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>understanding of the sub-cultures within the communities. Central to this  is also understanding their values and having an appreciation of how these </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>within the IMC framework becoming more prevalent in the marketing  mix, marketers therefore intend to develop specialised expertise in  this emerging marketing field in the near future.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relevance and resonance normally delivered through creative messaging and  content on the right channel, and at the right time. Ask involves interaction with  the brand, its websites, chat platforms, social media, or other digital engagement  channels. Act entails commitment to purchase such as on an e-commerce  website by clicking through from an advertisement. Advocate relates to loyal  customers who advocate via sharing, recommending and referring the brand.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>40</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>components that contribute to the calculation of Return on Marketing Investment  (ROMI), with PAR catering for the “Return” component, and BAR catering for the  “Marketing Investment” aspects (Kotler et al, 2017). Figure 15 below details this </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>41</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>know for its metrics of digital activity across digital channels. According to Stokes  (2018), it can be defined as “an established set of steps a user should take in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>performance using metrics such as Cost per Impression (CPI), Cost per View  (CPV), Cost Per Click (CPC), Cost per Lead (CPL) and Cost per Acquisition  (CPA).  Social media measurement metrics are related to these concepts, whilst  they include these, they also have specific metrics depending on the Social  platform. These are mainly engagement specific metrics such as likes,  comments, shares, posts, followers, or retweets.   According to IMH (2020) data in Figure 16, 41% of marketers evaluated </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer performance based on specific Social Media Engagements such as  content likes and comments, with a further 25%  evaluated on the basis of reach,  impressions and views.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>These measurements mainly fall into Kotler et al’s (2017) BAR category that  constitute brand actions, shifting the measurement of returns to purchase action  ratios. In Digital marketing funnel terms, this is considered to be top of the funnel.  Clearly not all marketing activities require conversion to sales and may be limited </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>42</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to BAR measurements, however, as more marketing budget moves towards  Influencer marketing, PAR measurements will become necessary.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>tend to be tied together, with payment based on reach (impressions), frequency  (number of adverts), and penetration metrics (% of customer reached).  In terms  of Digital performance marketing, budgets are usually calculated on the basis of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>well tracked funnel metrics such as CPI, CPC, CPL, CPC etc (Stokes, R. 2018),  with full digital funnel tracking giving detailed PAR metrics.   If Influencer performance is tracked on a BAR basis, this would need to include </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>both Digital Media and Social Media engagement metrics, whereas it becomes  evident that if ROMI measurements are required to be calculated for influencer  marketing activities, then Digital marketing PAR metrics (Digital funnel) will need  to be included.   It however remains unclear what best practice is with regards to measuring, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>tracking, and paying influencers as there are accounts of Celebrity influencers  who have gotten paid over $1 million simply for posting content due mainly to the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>size of their audience and their category, this falls into the 27% in figure 16 above.   Finally, as identified by Campbell and Farrell (2020), apart from providing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>audiences, influencers can also act as Social media managers, content  producers, strategist, and community managers. These services can attract a </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>separate marketing fee, or could be included as part of the overall contract.   There emerges distinct categories of contracting and payment for influencers that </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>could be used in combination for influencer contracting and remuneration, these  are audience based, performance based, and services based.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>43</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a blend of existing media metrics, social media performance measures, and  content services is expected.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Campbell and Farrel (2020) identify several DIM risk factors, they state  that the growth in Influencer marketing brings with it increased public  visibility that could tarnish a brands image if they have close associations </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with individuals prone to indiscretions, or are part of a scandal. With  celebrity influencers in particular, due to their status and following, a  brands reputation and credibility could face serious risk and  consequences. This is especially true should the influencer deviate from  expectations and act in a morally questionable or reprehensible manner.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>44</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>various social media channels at different times according to an agreed  content schedule, promoting content to increase engagements such as  likes, shares and retweets, and managing and growing the community by  engaging with users through responding to posts and comments in a  timeous and relevant manner.   Some influencers may have the capability themselves or a team in place </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to do all of this for a campaign partnership with a brand. Others may not  offer any of this except for the community engagement aspects. In some  cases as a condition of collaboration, influencers may insist on end-to-end  management and creative control with minimal oversight from the brand in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>order to ensure messaging credibility to maintain their authenticity. Brands  on the other hand may not be willing to relinquish creative power, or  conversely, could give absolute creative freedom to the influencer. The  circumstances vary, however, it would make sense that more experienced  influencers with stronger capabilities and proven track records should  enjoy a higher degree of creative freedom. Brands on the other hand may </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>allow more creative flexibility to Influencers that they have been working  with for longer periods of time, and who display an appreciation for, and  an alignment to the brand values and ethos.    Campbell and Farrel (2020) suggest that whilst developing brand </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communications content, too much involvement from many people without  clear guidelines in place risk diluting brand values, positioning and  meaning, and deviation from business goals and ethos.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>45</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>of these different marketing mix elements. It is expected that marketers  intend to put in place Influencer marketing frameworks, policies and  guidelines to better manage and protect their brand reputation and  image online.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“the ability to harness the full capabilities of the business to provide the  best experience for the customer and thereby drive growth”. They claim  that doing so can reduce marketing costs by 10 – 30%, and can unlock  between 5 – 15% additional growth through leveraging 10 identified  marketing capabilities and enablers seen in Figure 17 </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>46</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The capabilities proposed include real-time strategy and brand insights,  always on content, iterative media management, unified customer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>measurement and tracking, and customer activation through targeted  customer product and pricing offers. The mentioned capabilities exemplify   DIM where the ability to achieve real-time brand and strategy insights  available from online communities exists. Content marketing on Social  media for DIM is delivered in an interactive and always-on manner with  communications needing to be relevant and purposeful to the online  community. Performance measurement and tracking utilises paid, owned </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and earned media metrics. Customer promotion capabilities exist through  targeted and personalised product and price offers, as well as coupons.  Cohesive marketing operations with inter-departmental and inter-agency </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>operations functioning in cross-functional ways that leverage data, and are  centred around the customers experience, are all hallmarks of modern  marketing. Importantly, agile teams that deliver in rapid test and learn  modes are key enablers to successful modern marketing.   The research has shown that organisations involved in Influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing tend not to have dedicated departments or functions driving  Influencer Marketing initiatives or budgets (IMH, 2020). Given the cross-</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>functional nature of influencer marketing which straddles brand  communications and strategy, media and advertising, sponsorships and  public relations, and digital marketing, cohesive operating models become  a necessity for effective Digital Influencer marketing. The real-time and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>interactive nature of online communities and social media means that  marketing for these channels require agile working approaches to  performance measurement, tracking, content marketing, and brand </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communications.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>47</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>have a role to play in ensuring successful Digital Influencer marketing.  Influencer marketing as a modern marketing tool requires agile, data- enabled, cross-functional, and real-time modern marketing  management practices to be successful.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>considerations surrounding associating with influencers involved in  contentious issues, this risks damaging brand perceptions.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>or other incentives such as event and hospitality. Consumers view  sponsored material as advertising (Hwang and Jeong, 2016), and may be  sceptical and less likely to engage. Leading Influencers are also found to  be less compliant in their disclosure in order to improve their online </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>engagement rates (Hwang and Jeong, 2016).  For influencers, authenticity is an important aspect of building and growing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>their customer base, according to Stubb et al (2019), this  involves walking  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>48</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a tightrope between the needs of the brand, the followers, and the  influencer. Online sponsored content can sometimes appear innocuously </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>overall post. This could lead to consumers being unaware of the  advertising intent of the message. This brings about ethical  considerations, particularly as research shows that disclosures affect  consumers attitudes and behaviours, and that their responses depend on  the type of disclosure. Hwang and Jeong (2016) identify 3 different types  of disclosure, these are simple disclosures that inform consumers that  content has been sponsored, disclosures that provide more information, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>such as honesty claims and detail related to product or service quality, and  finally, disclosures that inform customers on the type of sponsorship and  compensation received.   The traditional advertising industry is well regulated, and serves to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>amongst other functions, protect consumers from false advertising and  poor advertising practice. The Advertising Standard Authority (ASA) or the  National Association of Broadcasting are bodies to whom complaints can  be directed. Governance for the type of disclosures and content  influencers disseminate is largely left up to the Social media platform  providers to self-regulate via their community rules and terms of services. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>It remains to be seen as DIM grows, whether this form of governance  model is adequate to protect brands, their reputations, and consumers, or  whether brands and local advertising industry bodies would need to play  a more active role in the governance and compliance of Influencers.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>49</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>views or clicks. This can lead to higher compensation for influencers who  charge on audience or performance, resulting in financial loss for brands.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Hypeauditor.com who provide influencer discovery, selection, verification  and campaign management tools at a cost. These platforms offer brands  the ability to do analysis by providing data of influencer audience gender,  age, location etc. They check Audience Quality Scores (AQS) that  analyses influencers on four categories i.e. Engagement Rate, Active  Audience, Growth, and Authenticity on platforms such as Instagram,  YouTube and Twitter (Amok, 2020). Given the existence of these platform </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>tools, the high prevalence of influencer fraud comes as an anomaly. A  reason for this could be that marketers are not aware of these platforms  and have limited skills and training in using them.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>therefore intrinsically tied to the credibility of the source i.e. Influencer, and  subsequent behaviour and intentions of the consumer. It stands to reason  therefore that the efficacy of influencer communications and messaging  would be poor for the brand should an influencers credibility be low, this </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>could also negatively impact consumers perceptions of the brand and  adversely affect its reputation.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>50</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>impact the influencers credibility if not addressed effectively. Also,  severing relationships with an Influencer may be met with retaliation that  could could tarnish a brands image. Influencers may also act in their own  capacity, in a controversial manner, advocating for contentious causes.   This could draw consumer backlash that might affect associated brand  perceptions. There is also the risk of influencers being misleading in their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>content communications drawing consternation and action from online  communities.   The ethical, legal, contractual and governance aspects of Influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing management to cater for these risks are still in their infancy with  a limited body of knowledge.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>risk, a trend towards developing more stringent legal contracts to  govern brand-influencer relationship will occur.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>51</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>which identified specific challenges in these areas when conducting DIM  campaigns. The discussion then covered modern marketing cababilities and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>factors such as influencer disclosure, financial risk, and ethics were highlighted.    There are 5 research propositions that emanate from this,  these are summarised  below under high level developed categories.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>near future.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>52</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing  Growth and  Development </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(IMGD)  Influencer Risk Influencer  and Marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer  Compliance Performance &amp;  Management Payment </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing  Best  Practices </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing Marketing  Capabilities Policies and  and Enablers Guidelines </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(IMCE) (IMPG) (Source: Authors Own)  In this context, the overall research objective is to explore Best Practices for </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital Influencer Marketing Management. The aim of this research is therefore  to better understand some of the following in the context of South Africa  • How Digital Influencers are being selected, and the specific marketing  objectives that are most suited to the use of specific Digital Influencers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>53</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Measuring the key success factors of Digital Influencer campaigns, and  the business value that can be derived from using Digital Influencers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Managing brand safety and reputational risk, and other challenges such  as influencer fraud, legal, regulatory and compliance requirements when  using Influencer Marketing   • How marketing departments can be structured to manage and leverage  Digital Influencer Marketing across marketing functions  • Ethical impact and dimensions of influencer marketing disclosure   Below table 2 shows the derived qualitative questions that have arisen through </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the literature review. The propositions are coded with the appropriate  abbreviations derived from the proposition categories.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>54</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Code Proposition Category Question/s    1. What is the strategic role of DIM in yours or your customers Brand and IMC </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Strategies?   IMGD Influencer Marketing Growth and  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>2.</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Development  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>6.</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Payment    7. How do you or the organisations you work with go about selecting influencers?  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>8.</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>IMPG Influencer Marketing Policies and  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing?    Influencer Marketing Capabilities and  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>for DIM?   IMCE  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>when using influencers?  IRCM Influencer Risk and Compliance  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>14.</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Management    15. Given your experience, is there anything you would like to add regarding DIM best </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>practices?  GEN General Discussion </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>55  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
    </chapterTwo>
    <chapterThree>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>CHAPTER 3. RESEARCH METHODOLOGY</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Given that this research is directed towards theory building and contributing to  our collective knowledge in Marketing Management, it is inductive in nature,  therefore a qualitative research approach is followed.  The concept of Digital Influencer Marketing is relatively new and has only come  into mainstream marketing over the last decade or so. This means that  practitioners are still understanding this growing area, and are negotiating and  socially constructing its meaning as it develops (Neuman, 2009). In this research  context, a constructivist paradigm is applied. This approach acknowledges the  subjective, varied and multiple different meanings that may exist, and allows the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>research to integrate the complexity of differing viewpoints into the meaning- making process that ensures cohesive research outcomes. These different  worldviews can be seen in Figure 19 </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>56</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Crotty (1998) identify the process of meaning-making to be socially constructed  through multiples perspective, and that the researcher uncovers the participants  subjective experiences through the research process.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Account”.   The key aim of this research is to uncover and understands participants </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>viewpoints related to Digital Influencer marketing best practices. Participants  were engaged in their professional capacity to discuss their specific context of  the subject, therefore, the interview questions which are developed by the  researcher were used as guiding questions in a semi-structured manner to allow  for natural dialogue. This allowed for open-ended discussion, and clearer  interpretation of the results. Paton (2002) says that “Purpose and audience, then,  guide design and analysis”.  The primary source of data is the qualitative interviews, industry reports on DIM, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and open-ended data such as DIM videos and guideline documents. These were  be consulted to form a richer picture of the DIM environment. Personal </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communications between the researcher and research participants and non- research participants also formed part of the inductive sensemaking process from  which codes and themes emerged.   The data analysis process was both inductive and deductive. Whilst the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>conceptual research framework and its themes have been deduced through an  analysis of the available literature and industry data, these acted as a lense from  which to inductively explore the subject and gather data. As the themes emerged </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>57</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>from the data collection process, participants meanings took precedence over  research or literature ascribed meanings.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the data, ascribing meaning to it, and objectively reporting on. This required  ongoing reflexivity to ensure that the researchers experiences, values, and  biases do not unduly shape the direction or outcomes of the study.   Finally, this research endeavours to provide a holistic account of DIM best </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>practices, in the context of South African marketing practitioners, through the  lense of the participants. Factors that emerge that have not formed part of the  study is reported as part of the research outcomes and further work. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>60 – 90 minutes. Personal communications such as email or calls with  participants or experts also formed part of the research where necessary. This  mainly supported the process of reflexivity in order to ensure a holistic account.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>aggregate information of employment within the formal sector which is 11,22  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>58</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>million, as at Quarter 1 2020 (StatSa, Quarterly Labour Force Survey, QLFS  Quarter 1: 2020). This breakdown covers all major industries including </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Finance, Community and social services, and Private households. Marketing  professionals can be found in all the abovementioned industries. Marketing  however also makes up an industry of its own through specialised marketing,  advertising, media and communication agencies. In terms of the labour force  surveys, employed marketing professionals are aggregated under the major  industries themselves eg. Trade, whilst the services the marketing industry  provides is aggregated under “finance and other business services”.This  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>includes real estate and insurance services.In breaking this down further, the  labour force surveys identifies the job categories of Manager,Professional,  Technician, Clerk, Sales and services, Skilled agriculture, Craft and related trade,  and Plant and machine operator. These collectively make up the formal </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>employment sector.   Marketing professionals can found amongst 3 job categories , these are Manager </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(1,463 million), Professional (884 000), and Sales and Services (2, 667 million),  which collectively account for a population of 5,014 million employed in jobs that  may include marketing services personnel. This does does not include  unemployed marketing professionals. The labour force survey does not provide </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>any further breakdowns that is able to provide insights into the marketing services  industry or professionals.   The marketing fraternity of professionals in South Africa is somewhat fragmented </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with no reliable data as to its size, composition, and breakdown. Empirical  research on the profession is lacking, with a limited number of self-regulating  bodies representing the industry. Furthermore, many categories of marketers  require little in the form of formal qualifications and accreditation. The industry is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>diverse with entry points into the profession coming from a variety of formal  education fields such as creative arts, multimedia design, communications  science, business and commerce, information technology, and engineering – to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>59</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>name a few. This also leads to marketing job functions and titles that are not  standardised, and in the case of Digital marketing, are still emerging.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that aims to represent the marketing industry and to accredit its professionals.  Membership and accreditation is however discretionary. It therefore represents  only a small but growing part of the entire industry with approximately 328  registereds members of which 240 are approved with professional designations  (MASA, 2020). Not all marketers choose to register with the organisation. Other  optional industry self-regulatory bodies include the South African Marketing  Research Association (SAMRA), Direct Marketing Association (DMA), the Mobile </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing Association (MMA), the Internet Advertising Bureau of South Africa  (IAB), and the Advertising Regulatory Board (ARB). MASA however is the only   professional marketing body for Marketers in South Africa that is recognised by  the South African Qualification Authority (SAQA).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Whilst statutory professional registrations is on the cards for marketing  professional with an estimated completion date of 2023 (Du Plessis, MASA  2020). Due to the current optional nature of marketing body membership, the lack  of accreditation requirements for marketing professionals, the flexibility and  diversity of qualification and professional education requirements in the  marketing fraternity, and the lack of standardisation in terms of marketing job titles </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and roles, specific population data supported by empirical research is presently  unavailable. Although this empirical population data gap exists, from consultation  conducted with MASA in an attempt to understand the marketing sector  population, it is estimated that there are approximately 4500 – 5000 marketers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>employed in corporate companies in South Africa, with an additional 1500 – 2000  employed or working in the marketing agency, advertising, and creative design  industries. This amounts to a total of between 6000 – 7000 employed and active </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketers in South Africa. Seperately, MASA also estimates approximately 5000  – 7000 students currently enrolled for marketing related studies at Universities  and Colleges in South Africa. Whilst these estimates are anecdotal in nature, they </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>60</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>are informed by the only recognised professional body that exists in South Africa  for marketing, they can therefore be considered as reliable.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>estimated at between 6000 – 7000 professionals. Population generalisability is  not an intended outcome of this research as is the case with quantitative  research. The research intent is to build theory in a specific area of interest which  will contribute to the marketing body of knowledge in the field of Digital Influencer  Marketing. Therefore, a sample of experts drawn from this population is adequate  for the intended research outcomes.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>specific context where the research needs to reflect multiple viewpoints of various  categories of marketers involved in Digital Influencer Marketing, a purposeful (or  purposive) sampling approach was used.  There are several a priori decisions  that have been made in relation to this research project which has informed the  research purpose and expected outcomes. Paton (2002) suggest that purposeful  sampling is a key distinguishing aspect of qualitative research, and that  qualitative inquiry focuses purposefully in an in-depth manner on relatively small </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>samples, which can even be the size of 1.   Choosing a precise purposeful sampling strategy to fit a specific kind of inquiry is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>recommended by Paton (2002). The sample size in this research report is made  up of 17 marketing practitioners from South Africa who were selected on the basis </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>of their involvement and experience in DIM, and who are able to provide an  information-rich context since the research sample is drawn from 3 categories of  marketers. These categories are a) Senior DIM experts who are specialised in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer Marketing, b) Advertising Agency Marketers, and c) Senior Corporate  marketers.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>61</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>In the first category of DIM experts, a sample of 5 was drawn from leaders working  in specialist Influencer marketing agencies, or with Influencer Marketing platforms </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>in growing, educating, and evangelising the marketing fraternity on influencer  marketing and represent viewpoints for leading practices in this field. Given their  commercial interests in DIM, it is expected that they are strong advocates for it.   The second category sample of 7 was drawn from experienced Advertising </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>agencies marketers who facilitate and integrate all forms of integrated marketing  communications (eg. Radio, Print, TV, Digital etc) into the marketing mix. The  selection criterion includes a requirement for them to have been involved in DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>campaigns over the preceding 12 months. Preference was given to participants  who have done more and larger DIM campaigns recently.  This cohort of  participants represents a balanced view of the role that DIM does and can play in  broader IMC plans, and within the marketing mix. They are also able to shed light </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>on the perceived efficacy of DIM as a medium when compared to other IMC  elements, and are able to provide insights into the views of their clients appetite,  interests, reservations and challenges in using DIM.   The third and final category of participants was drawn from corporate marketers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>across a range of industries. This group has some responsibility for their  companies brand image and reputation, marketing budgets, risk management, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and advertising and marketing compliance. Participants in this category have a  minimum of 5 years senior marketing experience, and have been involved in DIM  campaigns over the preceding 12 months. Preference was also given to  participants who have done more and larger DIM campaigns, more recently. It is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>expected that this cohort is able to provide insights into the strategic marketing  aspects of DIM.   As generalisability is not intended, and the research context is specific, the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>sample size and mix is adequate for the purpose of this research. Table 3 below  summarises the respondent profiles.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>62</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Participant Type No. to be  sampled </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer Marketing Experts: Senior DIM experts who are specialised in Influencer Marketing 5  Advertising Agency Marketers: Experienced marketers who facilitate and integrate all forms of integrated 7  marketing communications (eg. Radio, Print, TV, Digital etc)   Corporate Marketers:  Senior marketers who have some responsibility for their companies brand image &amp; 5  reputation, budgets, risk management &amp; marketing compliance. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>TOTAL Number of respondents 17  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Given the nature of the research, Creswell and Creswell (2018) suggest that it is advisable for the researcher as a key instrument to develop the research </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>questions.   A total of 14 questions which can be found in Appendix B have been developed.  These are based on the literature review covering the broad categories i.e. the  role of influencer marketing in strategic marketing, integrated marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communication, customer segmentation, brand communications and  management, marketing measurement, and marketing governance.  The  questions have been designed in a manner that encourages open ended </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>responses that could lead to deeper insights and themes.    </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Booking, and Interviewing.    Invitation Distribution entailed a call for interest by distributing via email  participation information letter contained in Appendix A with details of the  research This was sent to the membership managers of  the Marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Association of South Africa (MASA), and the Internet Advertising Bureau of South  Africa (IABSA) to distribute to their selected members. The researcher is  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>63</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>members of both these organisations. The invitation was also distributed to the  researchers network of marketing professionals via Email, Watsapp, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to express their interest, after which they were requested to provide some  information regarding their marketing experience. This included the Company  they work for, their job position, total marketing experience in years, Influencer  Marketing experience in years, and Influencer campaigns they’ve worked on over  the last 12 months.    This was followed up by the Participant Analysis and List Development stage </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>where all parties expressing an interest were analysed against the sample  categories and criterion, from which a list of 17 final participants was developed  and classified. This included details related to their suitability for the research.   The selected participants were thereafter sent a confirmation and the Participant </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>consent form in Appendix C for approval,  and a online meeting booking request  for a suitable time was negotiated with them via email or telephonically. At this  stage, the interview protocol was communicated to them as well. Participants who  were not selected were communicated to via email and telephonically. The  researcher however engaged in personal communications with them at various  points during the duration of the research, this was used to augment existing data,  support researcher reflexivity, and to ensure a holistic account of the context. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The final stage of the process was to conduct the qualitative interviews which  Creswell and Creswell (2018) define as “the researcher conducts face-to-face  interviews with participants, interviews participants by telephone, on the  Internet… These interviews involve unstructured and generally open-ended </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>questions that are few in number and intended to elicit views and opinions from  the participants”.   Each interview meeting lasted between 60 – 90 minutes long. A total of between </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>17 to 25.5 hours was required, which was spread over a 2 week period allowing  enough time for extended meetings should participants choose to engage in  longer discussions. This allowed time to accommodate the sharing of any </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>64</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>information being volunteered by participants, to conduct any follow up  discussion offered by them for clarification, or to continue any discussions that </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>contained in Appendix B.   The data collection process took between 4 - 6 weeks in total and covered the  aforementioned 4 stages. Records were kept via a password protected excel  document of participants who expressed interest, shortlisted participants, and  meta-data of the interviews held i.e. time, duration etc.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>categories. (Braun and Clarke, 2012)  state that TA is “a method for  systematically identifying, organizing, and offering insight into patterns of  meaning (themes) across a data set”. Using this data analysis method, the  researcher was able to understand the shared meanings and commonalities, and  the experiences of participants. The research covered different categories of  marketers involved in DIM i.e. Experts, Agencies, Corporates, who could have  different experiences, understanding and outlook towards DIM. The TA method  allowed for identifying patterns in the data, and for flexibility in analysing a broad  range of topics, or on specific phenomenon coming out of the data. In this regard,  it was well suited to the research project.    Through the use of TA, obvious, semantic and latent meanings of the data was </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>explored (Braun and Clarke, 2012) . The DIM industry and field is still evolving,  this means that the lexicon for it has not fully developed. Meanings ascribed to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>certain data was different for the various research participants, TA allowed for  uncovering and understanding the different meanings ascribed to the data.   TA was further used for both inductive and deductive approaches to research. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This research is a combination of both approaches where through a deductive  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>65</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>approach from literature and industry reports, a thematic map of ideas and topics  (see figure 18) that relate to DIM best practices has been developed, after which </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>new and previously undiscovered concepts, themes and topics emerged from the  inquiry during the interviews. This inductive approach ensured a holistic account  of participant data. A blend of theory based (deductive) and data based  (inductive) meanings is therefore applied to the research.  (Braun and Clarke, 2012) suggest a 6 step approach to TA, these are 1) </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Familiarising yourself with the data, where the researchers immerses  themselves in the data through things such as detailed review, listening, and note </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>taking in order to become intimately familiar with the data. 2) Generating Initial  Codes, which entails descriptive or interpretative analysis of the data to create  codes that adequately represent the data and its latent meanings. 3) Searching  for Themes that capture important patterns within the data and that can </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>represent various codes. 4) Reviewing potential Themes to define and quality  check themes to ensure that they are reflective of the data codes and are  appropriately descriptive of the specific topics and ideas they represent at a high  level. 5) Defining and Naming Themes to ensure themes and sub-themes are  distinguished, and that the themes are clearly defined and can answer the  research questions. Finally, 6) Producing the Report which writes up the results </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>of the data, and interprets the data into the research findings.    This research closely follows these 6 suggested steps. According to (Braun and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Clarke, 2012), TA Data-Analysis may be done manually or with the aid of  Computer Software to code, categorise and analyse the data once transcribed. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Given the relatively small sample size (n=17), using Software was not necessary.  Paton (2002) support this approach for qualitative research with a small number  of participant. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>66</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>in Table 3, this sample was selected as a representative of experts in the DIM  field from the different functions and organisation types within the advertising and  marketing industry. It was developed through a process of desktop research and  search of authors of news articles and blogs on DIM. Participants were found via  LinkedIn search criteria for Digital Influencer Marketing professionals, and via  referrals from the authors own network. An original list of participants was initially </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>created, however, several of the participants were recommended by many others  during preliminary engagements whilst formulating the list, prior to the data  collection, and were included in the final sample.   Broadly speaking, the data collection process involved 3 steps over a period of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The participants were initially contacted via email where their contact details were  available, or via LinkedIn to gauge their interest in participating and to collect their  contact details. An introductory note was sent briefly introducing the researcher, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the research intent itself, and requesting participants to express their interest in  participating upon which further information was sent. All 17 participants indicated  interest either via email or LinkedIn message, and requested more information.   Upon receipt of participants expression of interest, Appendix A containing the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>information sheet was distributed to them, together with the consent form  contained in Appendix C, and a list of possible interview dates and times from  which they could select a suitable one.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Step 2 – Participant Confirmation and Meeting Booking  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>67</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Most participants responded with their preferred date and time, and provided their  signed consent forms within a few days. Follow up reminder emails were sent to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>confirmed meeting preferences and their consent forms. Given the COVID  pandemic and Work from Home (WFH) environment, all participants were  comfortable and au-fair with online meetings using MS Teams. An online meeting  reminder together with the Interview guide in Appendix B was distributed to  participants, all of whom accepted the meeting request. The interviews were  scheduled for between 60-90 minutes each over a period of 9 days with 2  interviews conducted per day. With the exception of 1 participant who </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>rescheduled to a later date within the 9 day period, all the interviews happened  on schedule with no deviations from the initially proposed dates and times.   Step 3 – Conducting and Recording the Interviews </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The interview protocol followed a semi-structured approach, with all participants  initially being briefed on the various interview categories and questions. The fact  that the questions were not prescriptive was communicated at the onset of all  interviews, and also that they were expected to be referred to as guidelines for  the discussion which would be more natural and interactive. It was explained to  participants that they could feel free to discuss any DIM area in any order, and to  introduce any new insights at any point in the discussion. These questions were </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>also projected in a document via MS teams projection mode throughout the  interviews for ease of reference, and to bolster interviewee comfort levels.  Participants responded positively to the approach, and openly discussed their  points of views, and were receptive to follow-up and clarifying questions in all </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>categories.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>17.</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>68</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing, as a result, it was not considered to be DIM when they started doing  it as part of complementing their other marketing activities. In total, the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>doing DIM cumulatively for 97 of them (52%). Agency participants led the way  with most experience (37 years), followed by Specialist (31 years), and Corporate  trailing with the least experience (29 years).  On average, participants had 10,8 years marketing experience, and 5,7 years </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DIM experience. There were some who had up to 10 years DIM experience,  making them the early adopters as practitioners, with a few relative newcomers  having between 2-5 years experience in DIM. This is summarised in Figure 20 </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Data Recording and Transcription   A total of approximately 20 hours (1213 minutes) of interview time was held, and  recorded, with the average interview lasting 71,35 minutes. The longest interview  lasted 86 minutes, whilst the shortest lasted 45 minutes.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The interview recordings were then manually transcribed resulting in  approximately 195 000 words of text data emanating from the research. On  average, each interview generated 11 500 words, with the highest being 13600 </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>69</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>words, and the lowest being 7200 words. This points to the richness and  interactivity of the discussions held, with the amount of data and duration of time </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Data Analysis  To analyse this data, some textual data analysis software was used for the  project, mainly to understand key themes, this approach however provided very  little insights. Given that the interviews were highly conversational and interactive,  the transcribed data between the interviewer and interviewee was context  specific and required interpretation. Below Figure 21 provides an example of the  data, as well as raw and specified word clouds without many conversational </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>words.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>70</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>As envisaged, there were no discrete themes or categories from the textual  transcribed data (other than what was specified by the researcher) even when </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>these meant different things to the different respondents. Some respondents for  example interpreted Influencer Growth from the perspective of the Influencers  themselves, whereas others did so from a business point of view, and yet others  did so from a marketing or industry perspective.   The manual data analysis approach however proved to be more effective. This </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>followed the 6 step approach suggested by Braun and Clarke (2012).  This was done by consulting the source data and listening to original recordings </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and reading the transcripts in order to develop the results of this report. This was  based on the 5 themes of the research instrument (Appendix B). A manual  approach was possible given the relatively small sample size (i.e. n=17) as  proposed by Paton, M (2002).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Step 1 - Familiarising yourself with the data   The entire set of recordings were listened to again in random order by the  researcher, covering all 17. Notes captured during the interviews were also  referred to in conjunction with the recordings.   Step 2 - Generating Initial Codes  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This entailed analysing and interpretating the data and its latent meanings,  developing descriptive codes for sets of the data, and documenting “thick  descriptions” for each. These make up the final report.   Step 3 - Searching for Themes  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>After the key ideas and insights generated were adequately coded, it was found  that they were adequately described by the 5 core research themes within this  research conceptual framework (i.e. DIM Growth, Performance and Payment,  Policies and Guidelines, Capabilities and Enablers, and Risk and Compliance). </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>71</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>As all the data was well represented within the existing themes, there was no  need to generate additional themes.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>In order to quality check themes to ensure that they are reflective of the data  codes and are appropriately descriptive of the specific topics and ideas they  represent at a high level, segments of the various interviews were listened to  simultaneously in relation to the themes, which followed a specific order in the  interview recordings. This process of re-listening to the interviews took between  3 to 6 times the actual length of the recording itself due to the need to interpret  and cross reference all the related theme data from various participants to identify </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>whether any descriptive gaps existed between the data and the identified themes.  The outcome of this step indicated that the data found clear resonance with the  themes.   Step 5 - Defining and Naming Themes  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>As the themes and sub-themes were already named, these were already  distinguishable, and associated with the research questions for which intended  answers were sought.   Throughout the aforementioned process in Step 5, specific topics generated by </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the data were validated against the theme, and a sub-theme within it. This  allowed the researcher to surface categories within the themes, and to saturate </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>those categories by cross referencing data from all participants against them, and  thereafter ensuring the sub-themes accommodated them. Insights, ideas and  comments that were generated were synthesised and documented against the  DIM theme and sub-theme, and associated with the research questions it aimed </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to answer. The themes, sub-themes, and questions from the research conceptual  framework and instrument were once again found to be representative of the data  – as well appropriate to answer the related questions. This was validated since </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>there was no identifiable data generated that was unable to be associated within  the originally intended theme or sub-theme.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>72</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Finally, to negate the risk of overfitting the data into the conceptual framework,  once the initial results were documented descriptively, key aspects of the different </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>adequate and appropriate representation in the data. Data saturation was  achieved in this manner. Also it supported the researcher to ensure congruency  and accuracy was maintained in interpreting the data, and that all participant data  was appropriately represented throughout the report.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>via semi-structured questionnaire was validated. Also, the research questionnaire  as a suitable instrument with its core categories to describe and investigate the  DIM field was found to be appropriate.   Step 6 in the process entails Producing the Report, this will follow in Chapter 4. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencers themselves.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>73</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>this research is not directed towards empirical generalisability, instead, the  constructivist research paradigm being used is intended to uncover and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer marketing in a natural manner, rather than to explain causal  relationships that may exist.   Morse (2015) point out that these 4 qualities of research are important </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>aspects of achieving rigour.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencer marketing work, and has considerable Digital experience gained  over 2 decades. This prolonged experience and involvement in the  marketing and digital industry and domains ensures a high level of  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>74</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>credibility in the interpretation of the data. Member checking was done  through personal communications with participants not part of the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Peer-debriefing also occurred through engagements with academics,  professionals and colleagues in the researchers personal and professional  networks. Collectively, these measures support an overall high level of  credibility in the research outcomes.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The research furthermore did not collect biographical or demographic information  from the participants as it is not required for the purposes of the study. There are  also no vulnerable categories, contexts, groups or topics involved.  In terms of confidentiality, no individual responses were disclosed to participants, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>nor were they identifable to anyone other than the researcher. Responses are  also not attributable to individual participants in the final report. Pseudonyms such </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>75</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>as “Participant 1, 2,3” or similar are used where necessary.  Also, it is not the  intention of the research to collect any restricted or confidential information, if </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This type of research and its qualitative approach necessitated the identity of  participants to be known to the researcher, and hence, identifiable in the raw data  as this made up an important component of the analysis. Anonymity is however  protected as identities are not disclosed in this final report, nor are the  respondents organisation. Care was taken to ensure that inferences as to  participants identity cannot be made.   Working data such as interview notes, excel lists and transcribed raw data are </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>password protected at the document level. These and Interview recordings will  remain on a secure password protected PC and will all be destroyed after 1 year.   Since there are no sensitive topics or vulnerable contexts contained in the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>research, the measures of collecting only the data absolutely necessary,  protecting participant confidentiality and anonymity, and ensuring data is  adequately stored and disposed of ensures strong ethical standards throughout  the research project.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>76  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
    </chapterThree>
    <chapterFour>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>CHAPTER 4. DISCUSSION OF THE FINDINGS ......................... 77</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing specialisations deal with niche functions in areas such as marketing  research and insights, creative design and content, media and advertising, digital  marketing, and public relations. A major differentiator that emerges from this  research is that Influencer marketing can more effectively combine these various  marketing areas to design and deliver marketing communications in an efficient  manner by integrating the various marketing functions.   Research participants believe that given the growth of Digital channels, Influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Marketing will replace the standard advertising value chains, particularly because  DIM can improve consumer insights, message distribution, and content relevance  to target audiences in a quicker and more responsive manner than the “silo’ed” </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>approach using traditional advertising method (Participants 2, 6, 10). DIM is also  more trackable than other channels with digital performance and engagement  data  being available in real-time. This together with the ability to execute quickly </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>based on consumer insights, to be flexible in working with influencers, to work in  a more agile manner, and to test and learn are seen as important differentiators  of DIM as well.  Importantly, the growth of DIM has implications for a re- organisation of the marketing process. This entails designing and focusing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>advertising and communications initiatives around customer niches and  communities, rather than marketing disciplines.  An expert research participant suggested that societies are formed around </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communities (Participant 11), and that in communities, there are hierarchies.   Within them, there are different types of participation from members, involving  people with varying degrees of influence. Brands it is believed, cannot be a  member of the community, they can however participate in activities through </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>77</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influential members of the community introducing them to the community. Online  communities are microcosms of real world communities, and for brands to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“serve as the mediators  of brand messaging and content into these communities  of interest” (Participant 1).   The aspects of cross functional integration, online brand communities, and value </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>chain disruption is probed and discussed within this research, it also serves to  inform the DIM management best practices.   Due to the pervasive nature of Social media and Digital channels, all Influencers, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>even those with predominantly offline activities such as sports, participate in the  online ecosystem. This makes them Digital Influencers as well, therefore, the  terms Influencer marketing and Digital Influencer marketing can be used  interchangeably. This is supported by the research, with all participants stating  that social media activity is implied and expected in all forms of influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing campaigns. In terms of defining influencers, these could range from  prominent people like famous celebrities, TV actors, and Radio DJ’s, to leaders  within small communities, musicians, and topic experts as explained by research  participants. The consensus from participants within the research on defining  influencers can be summarised as follows   An “Influencer” is anyone that has influence over consumer perceptions </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and attitudes towards brands, its meanings, and its products, services.  Through aspects such as their expertise, fame, societal status, tastes, or  personality, they have influence over consumers lifestyles, behaviours,  values, and their choices. They play a role in shaping peoples goals and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>aspirations through the content they create and share, most notably, on  Social Media platforms.   Through their content, Influencers influence what people consume, how they live, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>what they think about the world around them, and their goals and ambitions.  Informed by the research, the below Figure 22 summarises the various types of  impact that Influencer can have on consumers  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>78</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>competing interpretations, fragmentation in standards between providers, and a  lack of consistency in how DIM is conducted.  There was broad consensus  amongst the expert research participants that common best practices in this field  with assist marketers to improve the efficacy of their marketing strategies, and to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>realise better returns on their marketing investments through more effective  influencer marketing strategies.   This clearly points to a need within the marketing industry participants to better </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>define best practices for Digital Influencer Marketing.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>annually (Humanz, 2020) for DIM with the key driver of growth being the ability of  marketers to reach and engage more authentically with audiences. Influencers  help marketers to break through the increasing clutter of online advertising, which </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>has recently seen huge growth due to the COVID pandemic. This has resulted in  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>79</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>more traditional forms of media such as outdoor advertising, in-store advertising  and merchandising, and events being relegated. Due to their low efficacy,  they </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>ability for advertisers to realise, or understand how to achieve return on marketing  investment (ROMI) from DIM, is seen to be one of the main restrainers of growth  (Participant 6, 10). This together with lack of knowledge and the resource  intensity to develop, execute and manage influencer marketing campaigns are  stated as barriers by almost all research participants. Many companies are  however trialling DIM in a low-risk manner, with those who are seeing successes  and ROI scaling up their investments in this area significantly. They are doing so </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>by working with specialist Influencer Agencies, PR companies, and Media  Agencies to execute DIM campaigns.   Specialist Influencer Marketing agencies who participated in the research </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(Participants 10 and 11) are seeing YOY revenue increases and volume of  campaigns doubling and in some cases more over the preceding 3-5 year period.  An influencer marketing expert from a leading global advertising agency network  (Participant 2) says that every client brief they receive now includes a requirement  for Influencer marketing, with some clients insisting that their marketing  campaigns are influencer led. This of course displaces the budget for more  traditional “above the line” (ATL) type marketing activities. They are also seeing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>what they term “signals of growth” that point to future growth, some of which  include receiving more incoming requests from prospective clients than they are  searching for. They note the inclusion of Influencer marketing on media  schedules, as well as the increased support from Social platforms to whitelist </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencers in order to amplify their content. They is also a high number of new  Digital Influencers coming into the industry as Influencer marketing is becoming  a career path for many who deem it their job. In many cases, it may be in addition </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to another career, and for some it could be their exclusive job and main source  of income (Participant 1).   Participant 4, a leader in “passion based” marketing eg. sports, highlighted the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>shifting media landscape as a result of COVID 19, stating that they have seen a  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>80</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>direct uptake of the use of DIM in marketing activities since the onset of the  pandemic. This is particularly for younger target audiences who don’t necessarily </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relateable. Accordingly, Influencers who mirror consumers perception of  themselves in these target audiences are effective at getting and maintaining their  attention. This is a consistent theme throughout the research.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>initiatives – to name a few. It can also be used to drive product trial, online  registration and purchase, and education. Interestingly, there appears to be a  shift away from a channel driven approach to marketing eg. TV, Outdoor, Digital,  Radio etc, towards a “channel agnostic” approach that is driven by content. Digital </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and Social Media has accelerated the fragmentation of audiences, bringing about  niche online communities, access to which is supported by DIM. It was mentioned  in some manner by all research participants, that through DIM, marketers can  reach previously inaccessible audiences. They can do this more meaningfully,  and in an authentic manner based on the trust relationship between the infuencer  and the community.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Public Relations and Digital Influencer Marketing  In PR, DIM supports existing communication strategies by giving marketers the  ability to amplify awareness on Social channels, it is seen as a complementary  tool to other media and advertising initiatives (Participant 16). It also enables </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketers to deliver messages with more depth than would have otherwise been  possible with more traditional type media. Product reviews and customer   testimonials are good example of this. PR practitioners tend to work through </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>media journalists to deliver their communication, they normally need to adhere to  restrictive guidelines and story scripts which makes it difficult to communicate the  messages they would like to, losing much value as a result. They therefore find </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>81</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that the ability for them to use influencers to disseminate their messages directly  and in a more targeted manner to customers via DIM is extremely valuable. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>access to consumers was previously not possible for them.   Customers reached via DIM are also seen as more receptive and engaged as  they have opted in to receive communications from an influencer who they deem  credible and / or trustworthy. Another value driver to using DIM for the Public  relations fraternity is having more scope and control of the communication  messages itself. When working with media journalists, they are unable to overtly  “push” brands or products, and to communicate in meaningful detail about the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>benefits of a product, service or event (Participant 3).   The use of DIM in PR is expected to grow with increasingly creative and novel </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>ways to use influencers being applied (Participant 1). Marketers are taking a more  focused approach moving away from the “A-Listers” with large audiences, into </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>more niche audience type influencers who represent smaller more focused online  communities (Participant 9). Given the COVID pandemic with people falling on  tough economic times, becoming an influencer is seen as a way to make some  income. Cases cited are a fashion retailer (Zara) allowing influencers to earn  revenue through promotional codes, or influencers in very niche areas such as  house cleaning being relatively successful.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>From a skills perspective, Participant 1 pointed out that PR practitioners are  looking to differentiate themselves in the way in which they do influencer  management and marketing. Influencer tracking, measurement and analytics are  cited as critical success factor. This allows them to develop and communicate </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>value added insights to organisations. These are used to improve their  advertising and marketing on an ongoing basis. Developing the skills to be able  to do this well, with cost effective tools that cover Social, Digital, PR and DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>specifically, is seen to be a key development opportunity. This results from  current PR tools monitoring mainly online, print and broadcast media and not  being effective at tracking Digital channels. These include Social Media tools  such as listening, reporting, community management, and analytics.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>82</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Aside from tools, the ability develop and maintain relationships with influencers  is touted as one of the unique selling propositions (USP’s) for PR practitioners.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the results they can achieve from the influencer ecosystem. This is achieved  through personalised interaction and relationship building with brands.  All the PR research participants firmly believe that DIM should be PR-led and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>aligned to PR processes citing the parallels between them in terms of their  objectives i.e. Generating Talkability, Newsworthiness, Improving Sentiment, and  Increasing Share of Voice.  Brand Marketing and Digital Influencer Marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>In Brand Marketing, many participants saw the role of Influencers in their  marketing mix as an effective channel to help them “build meaning” around their  brands (Participant 5, 14,15). Using DIM certainly offers brand marketers the  campaign reach and awareness, however,  the research found that their focus is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>equally on the brand fit, the association, and the endorsement value that they  derive from influencers. This is akin to Kotler et al (2017), Brand Advocacy Ratio  i.e. BAR metrics as discussed in Chapter 2, Figure 15.    Whilst recognising the need for long term relationships, brand marketers are </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>acutely aware of the brand risks involved in working with influencers. They  therefore opt to work with Influencers on a campaign by campaign basis </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>developing the relationship over time, as opposed to upfront Brand  Ambassadorship type models.   Participant 3 cited a case study in which DIM was used to “resuscitate” the brand. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The brand was not top of mind and its relateability to customers was eroding. The  DIM campaign showcased the brands creativity and positively shifted customer  perceptions in the respective target markets, leading to an improvement in brand  sentiment therein.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>With its ability to offer highly targeted and contextually relevant online reach, DIM  is expected to grow in terms of the brand awareness type value that can be </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>83</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>achieved through its use as a channel for wide audience reach. This was likened  to TV advertising by some participants. A participant who manages several </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>experiencing explosive growth” in this context. There are also “bespoke” DIM  opportunities with individuals that have a brand fit. This would involve a closer  brand “tie-in”, and would contribute more meaningfully to building brand meaning.  Influencers with  high levels of “Social Currency” through wide social acceptance  and relevance, and low levels of controversy are ideally suited to represent brand  marketing activity. They are able to help brands to not just drive up share of voice,  but to shape narratives, and shift sentiment positively. Accordingly, DIM is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>expected to grow within the IMC mix in both these directions i.e. Broad Reach  type advertising for share of voice, and Niche or bespoke type tactics for  engagement and sentiment. Unlike advertising, with DIM, the content is always  available and accessible on Social media, therefore, there is long term value of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the content and its impact. The potential reach upside of brand content through  sharing is another important value driver of DIM for Brand marketers, this allows  creative content to reach far beyond initial paid audiences.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Advertising Media and Digital Influencer Marketing   Digital Influencer maketing is fast making its way into advertising schedules,  becoming a stable feature in media channel selection. As one participant put it  (Participant 16), it is “another bullet in the chamber” for marketers to be able to  reach consumers. Influencer marketing should also be seen as complementary  channel to other forms of marketing as it can be used effectively to support all  types marketing activities.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>A key benefit of DIM to marketers as an advertising channel, is that it can reach  previously inaccessible niche audiences. Typically, this is done through multiple  smaller (eg. Nano) type influencers. Media practitioners are also able to profile </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and target audiences with previously unavailable precision, this takes market  segmentation to a new level.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>84</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Using Influencers as purely an Advertising mechanism does however have its  drawbacks. It impacts the perceived Authenticity of an influencers message, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>in this area argued that pure brand advertising on paid for media is very low on  the authenticity spectrum, whereas real customer testimonials will be very high  on authenticity. Using Influencer marketing as an Advertising channel would  definitely score higher for authenticity than brand message advertising would. As  a result, they generally receive at least 4x the engagement rates (Participant 9).  Of interest is the fact that almost half of all internet users globally use ad-blockers  of some sort, this necessitates digital advertising to become more creative in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>order to break through the clutter. DIM is seen as one way in which this can be  possible. Figure 23 below shows the insights developed from the research  around the relationship between Authenticity and Engagement, with the research  participants concurring that high reach with quality engagement and authenticity </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>should be the aim of DIM campaigns  (Source: Authors own)  Platforms such as Facebook allowed relatively recently (Early 2020), the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>whitelisting of influencers, and the ability to buy additional reach for their  sponsored content. This means that brands are able to use influencers, and then </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>85</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>amplify or “boost” this content via paid for digital media advertising, essentially  giving them the best of both worlds.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The research identified a consistently strong use for Influencers with them  participating in various stages of marketing events. This can include promoting  the event in the run-up by supporting the brand to build hype, participating in the  events themselves by being featured, or by simply attending. They can also add  value by “reporting” on an event by sharing general content on Social media  whilst the event is happening, or producing expert type content during and after  an event. Different types of influencers are effective for different strategies, for </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>example, Celebrity influencers famous for their music or sport involvement can  be featured in an event such as a concert or sports match. Specialised influencers  who have expertise in a specific area such as fashion or motoring are effective at  producing content for a product launch type event eg. Clothing line or Vehicle. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Lifestyle type influencers are useful in “reporting” on events either live through  Social media streaming, or via post event content sharing.   Marketers “Experiential” knowledge, their understanding of the social landscape,  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and their immersion into the Brand cultures and sub-cultures is an often  overlooked but crucial component in DIM (Participant 14). These marketers are  able to unlock value by identifying the right influencers to attend events, who may </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>then bring several high profile friends with them that add exponential value to the  brand. They are able to easily recruit influencers through their network and  relationships, and are able to negotiate deliverables and create added value  effectively. This human centred relational approach to finding, selecting, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>contracting, negotiating, and management approach to DIM is agile in nature,  and a far cry from the highly functional, process, and technology orientated  alternatives. It appears to be more suited to event and sponsorship related DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>activities.   The value to consumers is also an important factor to consider at marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>events, through them, brands can offer customers the ability to meet and interact  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>86</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with celebrities. In the past, Brands would pay appearance fees to Celebrities,  more recently however, this is packaged to be included as part of DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Digital Influencer Marketing adds value to all marketing functions, Figure 24  below summarises the different DIM value drivers that originated from the  research </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>own)  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencers”. This typically focuses on generating and maximising awareness  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>87</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>for the brands, its products and services, and its marketing initiatives. Extracting  media value from DIM entails using Influencers to generate reach, drive content </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>online followers and community sizes, and in some cases, support improvement  in sales and purchase behaviours (Participant 3).   The second stage of DIM is the “Brand Endorsement and Content Creator”. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This stage moves away from brands mainly deriving media value from DIM, to  brands leveraging influencers trust within their fans or follower community. In this  stage, through closer partnerships, influencers authentically endorse brands.  They create relevant, entertaining, and / or educational content that is meaningful </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to their community, and that has high value for the brands they represent. The  benefits of this for brands are that through their association with influencers, they  become more trusted, and their content is seen to be less interruptive than  advertising messages. It therefore has a higher likelihood of engagement. The </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“long tail” of the brand sponsored content also has value beyond the short term  campaign objectives, this drives long term value (Participant 8).   The third and final stage of DIM growth is “Collaboration and Integration”. In </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>this stage, influencers  are seen by marketers as part of the “Brands marketing  team in the field” (Participant 13). They are loyal to the brand and share its values,  and can serve as their “antennaes” – or eyes and ears on the ground. Due to their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>closeness with niche customer audiences, Influencers can become strategic  decision making partners to the brands, helping them understand what is relevant  to their target audiences. They can also support them to design marketing  communications and content that will resonate with consumers. Influencers can </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>also serve as “First Customers”, able to trial company products and services in  order to give brands important suggestions and feedback on improvements.   Finally, due to being more in touch with their communities, Influencers can </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>provide brands with real-time research and insights on customer trends, topics,  preferences, affiliations, beliefs etc. Through this, marketers are able to tailor  advertising messages and communications strategies that find more resonance  with customers. An important and less recognised value stream from this level of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>88</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DIM maturity for marketers is that through having influencers as a brand  extension, the cost of having to employ knowledgeable staff in the different areas </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>identified through the research, and the associated influencer activity authenticity  curve  The research suggests that DIM maturity is not happening evenly globally or even </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>amongst organisations in similar industries and sectors. It is worthwhile noting  that an organisations “orientation” (eg. Product, Customer, Brand etc)  plays a  big role in their level and pace of maturity (Participant 10). Anecdotally, several  participants believe that organisations that are more customer orientated tend to  have higher levels of DIM maturity, with customer experience being identified as </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>an accelator of maturity. Furthermore, “Pureplay” digital market entrants are seen  as more mature early adopters of DIM (Participant 8,10,15).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>89</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and creativity and content. Marketers require strong knowledge in market  research and insights, digital media data, and marketing science - with a firm  understanding of digital customer engagement and path to purchase. Expertise  in Social Media policies, best practices, trends and norms is critical. Specific  knowledge of the different platforms (eg. Instagram, YouTube, Twitter etc) and a  deep understanding of the cultural influences related to the different digital </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>channels and their audiences is necessary. The main business skills that have  been highlighted is negotiation, project management, and relationship  managements skills. These are deemed as indispensable when it comes to  dealing with influencers commercially, gaining and sustaining their interest in a </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>brand, convincing them to participate in campaigns, activities, and events, and  managing the quality of their content, and the scheduling and publishing of their  output on the various digital channels (Participants 7,11,12, 17). Creativity and  content development has been universally emphasised throughout the research  by all participants, making it central to successful influencer marketing as one of  its main differentiators.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>With the exception of specialist Influencer marketing agencies, by and large,  seperate DIM skills and capabilities do not exist within organisations or their  agencies. It is generally expected that other departments integrate it into their  work, without much in the form of formal training or upskilling being planned in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>this field by any of the participants. This is despite its envisaged growth in scope  and scale by all participants. Participant 13, a senior marketing strategist for a  global FMCG brand that has hundreds of brands with thousands of products, said </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that DIM is being included in every single media schedule since the COVID  pandemic. This is due to its ability to drive the same kind of broad reach and  awareness as TV and Outdoor media, with the added benefit of being able to use </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>90</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>it for consideration, as well as purchase intent. Despite this, there are no plans to  build these skills.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>becoming more prevalent in the marketing mix, marketers therefore intend  to develop specialised expertise in this emerging marketing field in the near  future.  The research found that DIM is growing in importance within IMC due to its ability </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to generate multiple streams of value. It was also found that DIM touches on all  marketing functions, and that it is increasingly being used in novel standalone  and integrated ways in the marketing mix. Marketers however have no plans or  intentions to develop specialised expertise in this field in the near future. In </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>general, the research pointed out that they expect that DIM will be conducted  within the various existing marketing functions. It will be located mostly within PR  and Brand Management for the foreseeable future, with the necessary upskilling  taking place organically. They are however aware of the need for better  integration and co-ordination amongst the various marketing functions in order to  sustain the increased use of DIM, and to maximise its effectiveness.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>industries, the participants represented a broad view from across the DIM value  chain. There was understandably different and divergent views on influencer  marketing performance measurement practices, marketing objectives, and value </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>91</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>drivers for which DIM is being applied. There was also a variety of payment  models in use.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>measurement and payment for DIM would depend on, and be linked to, the  business and marketing objectives specific to the campaign. Broadly speaking,   although not clearly delineated with overlaps amongst them, 3 distinct schools of  thought emerge i.e. 1) DIM as a Media Channel, 2) DIM as part of a  Communications Strategy, 3) DIM for Brand Building.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>funnel metrics such as Cost per Mili (CPM), Cost Per View (CPV), Cost Per Click  (CPC), Click Through Rate (CTR), Engagement Rate (ER), Cost Per Acquisition  (CPA) etc which collectively measure the efficacy of the channel. Practices  include providing influencers with trackable links or pixels to embed into their  content, allowing click through and conversion measurement and tracking. As  DIM in this instance can easily be compared to other online and traditional media </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>channels. The media cost of the channel is one of the key deciding factors in  using DIM, with value deriving from a lower cost to reach, and higher engagement  on advertising. In certain instances, particularly for E-commerce type campaigns,  increase in online customer acquisition or sales can be an important measure. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This aligned to Kotler et al’s (2017) “Purchase Action Ratio” marketing measures  discussed earlier in this report.   Payment for influencers in this instance is exclusively monetary and tends to be </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>weighed-up in lock-step with other “paid media” channel choices. Marketing  practitioners select this channel based on media efficiency performance using  indicators such Influencers audience size, target audience, and engagement rate </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>92</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>– typically on the basis of large follower and community sizes (eg. Mega  Influencers). These indicators fit comfortably with media objectives of reach, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>seamless. Similar to other media platforms, pre-approved content is generally  provided to the influencer who in turn publishes (eg. Shares, Posts etc) according  to an agreed upon schedule.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>communication. Although all brand communications should be relevant to  audiences, this approach advocates for a focus on authentic and relateable  content, produced in partnerships between brands, influencers, and their  agencies. This approach is done to find resonance and achieve higher than </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>average reach and engagement for the brand. Advertising Value Equivalent  (AVE) metrics are specific PR related measures which are applied to DIM, where  the value of an influencers organic reach and community engagement (eg. Liking,  Sharing etc) is calculated in terms of what it would have costed if it were paid for  advertising. In DIM, Share of Voice (SOV) measures are analysed in the context  of a brands share of conversation, typically on Social Media channels. This is </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>calculated as a percentage of other brands in the same category, or with the  same or similar products or services. Sentiment is also an important element, in  that it measures tonality of coverage of content (i.e. Positive, Neutral, Negative).  As opposed to their media reach and value, influencers are selected for their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>affinity to their audiences, their authenticity, their engagement, as well as their  knowledge and expertise in a specific topic area (eg. Fitness, Fashion, Motoring,  DIY etc). As a result, niche influencers with smaller and more focussed audience </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>sizes are commonly used in this area (eg. Nano and Micro influencers). Payment  in this area can be nuanced, with a mix of product seeding where influencers  receive products that they can use and share the experience with their community  online, monetary payment in exchange for developing and posting content, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>93</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>for their time for engaging in online and offline brand marketing activities (eg.  Events, Press Briefings etc).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to the brands appeal, this enables brands to maintain their unique identity in the  eyes of consumers, and to create positive brand perceptions that enhance value  for their company through occupying brand territories for their products and  services in the minds of the consumer (eg. Quality, Luxury, Stylish, Premium, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Responsible, Affordable, Active etc). Typically, although not exclusively,  influencers who have large online and offline followings and are famous in some  area (eg. Musician, Actor, Sports star etc) are used to support brand building  initiatives as part of their broader brand marketing campaigns (i.e. Celebrity  Influencers). Some brand marketers however are circumspect on the use of  Celebrity influencers, preferring to select a number of well known influencers with </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>smaller followings, within smaller niche online communities, especially where  local relevance of the brand is of high importance. Marketers measure the  performance of these types of DIM engagements through the aforementioned  media and communications metrics for shorter term indications of results. The </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>main value drivers are however measured through brand surveys, brand tracking  reports, and brand valuations – all of which are long range performance  measurement tools as specified by Kotler et al’s (2017) BAR measures. In DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>specifically, Social Capital in online brand communities influences Brand loyalty  as a result of Participative Behaviour, Sense of Belonging, and Network Ties  (Meek et al, 2019). Brand influencers play an important role in the building of  social capital for brands. Payment to Celebrity or brand influencers are based on </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>94</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>brand endorsement, they are less transactional in nature as would be the case  for shorter term campaigns. This would include monetary compensation, but not </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>content creation per se as is the case with the other approaches discussed. The  influencers in this instance charge for their celebrity status, wide-ranging appeal,  or fame and expertise within the specific online and offline communities of  interest. As a result, their costs vary wildy and are negotiated as part of a longer  term relationship between brands and influencers. It is also common for  influencers to receive brand products which they actively use, to receive as gifts  access to local and international events and concerts, to receive hospitality at </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>brand sponsored or affiliated activities, and to be part of brand curated  experiences at no charge. This can include incentives such as travelling to exotic  destinations. In some cases, there is no monetary payment, particularly for lesser  known brand influencers who may only receive compensation through products, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and gifts of brand hospitality and curated experiences. Also, an influencer may  be a “friend of the brand” because of their affinity to the brand and its products or  services (Participant 12). They could receive care packages and be invited to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>events with no obligation or expectations. Brands however hope that User  Generated Content (UGC) will results from the Influencers experience with the  product or brand. In these instances, as the influencers are not paid for their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>services, Brands cannot expect to review or have a say in their content and  messages, if any.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>participate in Brand building activities, compared to only serving as a media or  communications channel for marketing campaigns. As pointed out, these  different approaches are not mutually exclusive, there may be instances where  for example a media channel approach to influencer marketing is applied to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>95</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>amplify a brand building campaign for reach, or a communications campaign may  include aspects of brand building via influencers, whilst at the same time driving </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>A prime example cited in the research is having a famous rapper wear a particular  brand and type of sneaker, the content of which is featured on Social media  channels, and which subsequently gets sold out. Participant 14 who has a long  term relationship with an Influencer say that when their influencer posts an  Instagram story of them visiting the brands retail store to get fashion  merchandise, those products are sold out within day. The brand is now deepening  their collaboration with the influencer to develop a co-branded line of products. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Clearly, there is a directly correlation between product sales and the influencers  activity. However, this is not the result of any overt purchase call to action. Whilst  this is clearly attributable to the DIM activity, this “product seeding” activity is not  directly measureable. Questions that arise then are what should marketers pay </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>for such a DIM engagement? In practice, mixed payment models are applied.   With this said, many of the research participants displayed a clear preference </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>towards a specific perspective in terms of how to measure and track, derive value,  and compensate influencers. This is presumably as a result of the specific  marketing discipline they are trained in and represent eg. Advertising, Media,  Creative, PR etc. The exceptions to this were the specialist influencer marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>agencies and platform experts, who displayed less bias towards a specific DIM  approach due to their exposure and experience to a wider cross section of  different marketing campaigns with varying objectives. This points to the fact that  a lack of knowledge in this field exists amongst non-experts, and that to improve </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a range of usage, performance, measurement standards, and value extraction  from DIM, more education for marketers is needed.    Although these different perspectives exist, a common theme emerging from the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>research is that influencer performance and tracking ought to be linked to the  business goals that should be set upfront. Therefore, media metrics, share of  voice, and brand measures ought to be seen in the context of success factors in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>96</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relation to the outcomes set out in the business goals. This approach ultimately  unifies the disparate perspectives into a meaningful marketing strategy.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that brands expect to derive from using influencer in their entirety, as opposed  mainly their audience size (eg. Followers, Fans etc) and reach. They argue that  the true value that brands get from using influencers is in the creativity and  content, their specialised competence (eg. DIY expert, Fashion Designer etc),  and the brand association value. They state that Influencers should be  compensated for these, and their work deliverables related to content production,  in addition to their audience. Thus, if the objectives were exclusively reach based, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>then purchasing more traditional digital media through “performance buys” may  be cheaper and more effective (Participant 5, 15).   In more mature organisations where deeper relationships are held with </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencers, there is the opportunity for influencers to also influence strategy,  product, and design. In this model, there can be shared risk and revenue flowing  between a company and the influencer. There have been several successful  examples collaborations between influencers and organisations who jointly come  up with a branded and unique line of products for example, where the basis for  the engagement is grounded in commercial outcomes. This might include referral  or affiliate programs, in such cases, success is dependant on the extent to which </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the influencer has a vested interest in the commercial success of the strategy  (Participant 14).   It can thus be concluded that some factors to consider in payment would include </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>compensation for   • Strategy and Insights  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Attendance or Appearance  • Content Deliverables, Production and Publishing    • Audience and Reach   • Online Community Engagement  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Brand Endorsement Value   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>97</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Commercial Performance   Given that the use of DIM is generally one part of a broader marketing mix, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>that the overall campaign performance could be the result of different marketing  touchpoints,  a promising avenue for understanding and attributing DIM value, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>tracking DIM performance, and establishing ROMI for DIM, is integrating it into  the organisations “Media mix modelling” (Participant 12).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a blend of existing media metrics, social media performance measures, and  content services is expected.  The research expected to validate that the industry was coalescing towards </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>standardisation in remuneration and performance measurement. In reality  however, it was found that the level of skills maturity and knowledge of DIM  amongst marketers is low, and that standardisation cannot occur in the absence  of a solid understanding of the different DIM capabilities and dependancies.  Whats more, it was found that DIM campaigns in practice are far too nuanced  and contextual for remuneration or measurements to be standardised. Also, that  the scope of different and creative ways that DIM can be applied has not yet been  fully explored. With that said however, participants did identify the need for certain  shared “rules of thumb” that are based on DIM campaign types, and which would  support more informed DIM remuneration and measurement.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>98</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>isn’t a common approach towards this. Finding influencers is seen as a challenge  for many. It is accomplished through a blend of direct relationships between  marketers and influencers, marketing networks, via agencies and partners,  agents representing one or more influencers, and influencer software platforms  (eg. Webfluential, Humanz etc). Each of these approaches have benefits and  drawbacks and requires marketers to firstly find influencers that match the  marketing objectives and campaign criteria with specific interest and /or expertise  in an area, then to analyse them for various factors ranging from audience reach  and target market, brand risk and safety, to costs. Platforms have developed </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>proprietary algorithms that collect Influencer data from Social Media channels,  and use that to rank Influencers based on various measures, such as their  audience size, location, and quality, their online behaviour, engagement rates, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>customer ratings, delivery history, costs and value, and content quality – amongst  a host of other factors. Off-system factors are equally important, such as whether  the Influencers are users of the brand products or clients, their location for geo- targetted campaigns, and other background information that might be relevant to  the brand and its objectives.   In some cases this is done manually, which requires specialist knowledge, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>expertise and relationships through immersion into DIM. In other cases, platforms  are used exclusively to find, analyse, and select influencers. The various  approaches have their respective merits and drawbacks, as an example, finding </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>99</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a digitally savvy influencer who is or will be moving into new house to talk about  their experience of a moving service or home renovation company is not </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>access to “A-list” celebrity type influencers who are typically represented by talent  agencies. On the other hand, software tools provided by platforms make  influencer analysis seamless through access to data such as audience and  followers, engagement rates and scores, and interests, passions and  preferences. Important checks such as whether the influencer has a criminal  record, history of misaligned content on their social feeds, and quality of their  content also need to be conducted. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The selection of influencers manually by marketers also introduce a level  subjectivity and bias into the decision making. The research uncovered a  tendency from marketers to specify names of known influencers they would like  to work with without defining their strategy and campaign objectives first. All </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>participants concurred that selecting the influencers should come towards the  end of the strategy and campaign design process, not at the beginning.  Subjectivity could also lead to  a lack of diversity in terms of influencer selection,  and lack of race and gender representation (Participant 17). Brands also expose  themselves to a considerable amount of “brand noise” by using the same known  name influencers who represents multiple companies concurrently.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Subjective selection can also yield positive results. One research participant says  that prior to selecting an influencer to work with, they personally watch them by  learning more about them through their online and offline activities. They also ask  others influencers who work with and are close to the brand for their experiences </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and opinions in working with the person (Participant 14). They follow this up with  using the platform tools to analyse their audience, following, and social media  history. An important learning from this approach is that brands could benefit from </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>developing and managing an “Influencer Watchlist”.   specified by the research participants </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>innapropriate by themselves for the selection, pricing, and management of  influencers. Whilst it is important to understand the influencers reach, in practice,  the research shows that from a strategy perspective, a more nuisanced approach </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to the selection of influencers is required from marketing practitioners. Participant  14, a brand manager representing a global fashion brand argued that an  Influencer who has a large following, and who may be a successful musician for  example, may not necessarily be known for their taste in clothing, using them </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>therefore to promote a new line of fashionable apparel would not be effective –  irrespective of their fame status. Factors that would be more important are the  Influencers image, their associations, their lifestyle, and their tastes. According to  Participant 14, immersion of marketers into the culture, and having the lived  experience by being part of the “zeitgeist” is an indispensable aspect of Influencer  scouting and selection. This participant in fact deters Influencers from mentioning  their brand, they much prefer that they are seen using their product, and that their  brand is a true part of the cultural experience taking place. In this way, they </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>believe that their brand becomes more relevant in an authentic manner, which the participant terms “cultural marketing”.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>scouting and selection to be based on the one hand on personal relationships,  subjective experiences, topical knowledge, and immersion into the culture and  lifestyle by marketers. This allows marketers to find and exploit DIM opportunities  in a creative and tactical manner that would otherwise not be possible. On the  other hand, selection based on platform software tools provide ready access to  influencer audience data, ranking, history, costs, and engagement rates for  marketers. This allows for effective and objective analysis, comparison, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>selection.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>platform data (eg. Twitter, Facebook etc). They should also vet both the  influencers and their followers for fraud and social media activity. Figure 27 below  shows the composition of Influencer Audiences as specified by influencer  platform experts that participated in the research </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>the influencer and the brand ensures that they engage more meaningfully on the  campaigns that they collaborate on in an authentic and genuine manner.  Campaign objectives needs to also be aligned to the “Influencer Mix” – which can </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>be a range of influencers selected to meet the different marketing goals. For  example, 1 or 2 influencers may be selected for their broad appeal and reach,  coupled with a selection of several smaller influencers for their content creation  capabilities and niche appeal. This could range from as few as 5 to 10, up to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>hundreds in some cases (Participant 11).  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>When selecting influencers, from a strategy perspective, marketers should also understand the types of influence that is required, broadly speaking, these fall </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Role Models &amp; Celebrities (Influencers who engender trust, mirror  consumers values, or are perceived to have positive intentions)   • Topic Experts (Influencers who are experts in a topic eg. Nutrition, Fitness. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Typicall with a professional right to speak to something eg. Michael Jordan  and shoes)   • Social Crowd (Influencers that are Customers, staff, or entertainers who </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>address relevant and topical matters)  The main selection factors can be summarised as follows </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Brand Selection Factors   • Campaign Selection Factors   • Risk Factors  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Audience Factors   • Personality Factors  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Design and Creative Factors   • Industry Compliance Factors  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Delivery Factors   • Pricing and Commercial Factors  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Background, Expertise and other factors   The research pointed out that these need to be managed within the 3 areas of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DIM campaigs i.e. Planning, Management, and Execution. Figure 28 display the  research outcomes in terms of the relevance of the factors within the 3  abovementioned research areas </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>is the most important aspects of an influencers ability to influence their audiences.  However, the larger the audience size and reach of an Influencer, the lower the  perceived trust, authenticity, and reach.   An often overlooked metric when selecting and analysing influencers is their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“True reach”. Despite an influencer having a large number of followers, due to  content filtering algorithms and user settings, the actual reach on their Social  media posts may be a fraction of their audience size. This is helpful to marketers  to set KPI’s around the performance of their campaigns.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>image and reputation is maintained, protected and enhanced. Influencers at the  same time need to be authentic and transparent so as to ensure that they are </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relevant to their community, and not to come across as overly scripted in the brand related content that they share. As publishers themselves, influencers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>resonate with their online community. They are in a position to guide brands on  this. What cannot be overlooked is the limited context of marketing practitioners,  which a few participants claim are far removed from the realities, perspectives,   and lives of customers (Participants 13, 14, and 17). They argue that many senior  marketers in the industry whether in corporate or at agencies, are generally older  and disconnected from what is actually going on, particularly with younger and  more niche type audiences. They need to get out of their “ivory towers”, away </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>from their desks and emails, to “smell, taste and feel” whats going on on the  ground (Participant 14). Influencers can play a vital role in helping marketers to  bridge this gap, and to help them understand new generations of customers much  better.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Brands on the other hand understand their objectives, intent, messaging, values,  and marketing communication strategies. Whilst many of the research  participants are proponents of a high degree of creative freedom for influencers,  others argue they ought to be subject to the same constraints as creative  agencies, who receive and interpret briefs, and who produce content that is  aligned to the brand and its marketing objectives. On the other side of the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>spectrum are marketing practitioners who suggest that too much creative  oversight defeats the main purpose of using influencers, which is to create  genuine endorsement through authentic content. They advocate for minimal  intervention from brand in the creative output so that influencers can bring an </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>element of truth and authenticity in their communications. Withut this freedom,  they can be seen as “selling out” to the fans and followers within their community.  This can  cause an online uprising against such influencers, colloquially termed </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“cancel culture” – which refers to ostracising people on the basis on of their  behaviour or statements, typically done via social media. This is contagious and  can have far reaching consequences, causing serious reputational and financial  harm to brands. The recent Clicks Tresemme online advertising bungle, or the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Outsurance collaboration with GBV accused Katlego Maboe, bears testament to the power of cancel culture on Social media.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>room, and a “soft” brief giving the influencer considerable space to interpret the  brief. Consideration factors impacting this are the relationship between the brand  and influencer, whether they have used the person in the past, the influencers  experience and professionalism, their previous work and quality, and the brands  that they have represented. Also, the brands sensitivity towards reputational  issues, their risk tolerance appetite, and their customers attitudes and  expectations play a large role in calibrating the level of creative freedom they are </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>comfortable to provide. A brand operating in a highly regulated industry with  serious and professional clientele such as a large investment firm may for  example have different requirements to an FMCG company with a fun and  entertaining product. A theme regularly mentioned in the research was </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“Advertising and Creative Guidelines, Principles, and Parameters” that need to  be communicated to influencers, and followed by them as “Guardrails”,  whereafter, they should be able to follow their own creative style.   Irrespective of the approach taken to creative control and de-risking the process, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>a comprehensive upfront brief covering the marketing goals and objectives,  expected output, product and brand images, mood boards and storylines, art </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>direction, visual identity, copy suggestions, and other creative elements is  advised by all participants.   Content schedules that specify when and by whom content is expected to be </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>posted make the process predictable. This allows for brand review or legal sign  off prior to content being published. High levels of predictability should be sought  as a best practice (Participant 12), which further de-risks the process. In certain  instances, Brands specifically collaborate with Influencers due to their creativity </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>as an artist – such as a painter or musician, and their strength in content creation.  In this instance, higher levels creative freedom is an express intent of the  collaboration. Figure 29 describes the creative continuum related to influencer  marketing described by the research participants. Different research participants </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>found themselves at a different point within this continuum based on their industry and their specific needs </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Finally, a “Creative Framework” within which Influencers need to operate is  advised. This entails various parties in the marketing value chain working  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>together, with the advertising agency providing the “Creative Theme” to the  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Influencer. This is informed by the Brand strategy, which Influencers then  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>interpret in a human centred manner, applying their style and approach to create  content. This manner of “Applied Creativity”, which according to Titus (2007) is  uncertain, and requires uncommon sense, cognitive flexibility, motivation, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>knowledge. One senior research participant (Participant 9) from a specialist  agency suggested that an influencer can be  “A whole creative agency in 1  person”, and that brands stand to lose the core value of Influencers if they exert </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>too much control over the creative process and its outcomes.  This sentiment was  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>echoed in similar terms by most other participants.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The research hypothesis for “Influencer Marketing Policies and Guidelines” is listed below as follows </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>It is expected that marketers intend to put in place Influencer marketing frameworks, policies and guidelines to better manage and protect their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The research found this to be true with the participants, all of whom are actively  practicing DIM. There were several specifically dedicated Influencer Marketing  inititiaves being planned – particularly amongst the specialists. These included  development of DIM Playbooks and Creative Frameworks for example. Most of  the plans however involved improving existing marketing frameworks, policies,  processes and guidelines to better represent the specific DIM needs within them.  Marketers are therefore seeking to improve in general the way they brief, project </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>manage, conduct content planning and design reviews, and collaborate and  integrate DIM campaign and activities in order to improve brand safety.   The lack of a planned and concerted approach to improving DIM in terms </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencer selection, management, and quality control does raise concerns given  the considerable growth and increase in the use of influencers by marketers.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>understanding of consumer behaviours and trends, and being able to be sensitive to the socio-cultural, socio-economic, and socio-political environments.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>putting in place personnel dedicated to manage influencer relationships. This  assists them to more frequently leveraging the richness of insights they are able  to provide, and to reduce the lead time to develop, design, and execute a  marketing campaign (Participants 4,5, 14,15). The DIM industry is rapidly  evolving and growing, with several “gold-standard” case studies to learn from,  such as KFC’s #MakeitLegendary TokTok focused influencer marketing  campaign. This generated a reach of over 1,2 billion within a short space of time </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(approximately 6-7 months). Its success resulted from a clear brief on the use of  DIM for the brand objectives, a focus on a specific platform i.e. TikTok, and a  deep understanding of the relevant trends and culture which Influencers helped  them to unlock (Participant 15).  The ability for marketers to engage regularly with </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>peers in the marketing industry, to access and read the latest reports and case  studies, and to network at a local and global level with experts and marketers  who are applying DIM in novel ways are seen as strong capability enablers  (Participant 9).   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencer talent, and on nurturing meaningful and personal connections with  them (Participant 14). Negotiating Influencer content usage rights on various  brand, media and partner channels is an important consideration as well </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(Participant 11 and 14).   The ability for marketers to understand the full digital customer journey, and the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>capability to design end-to-end digital experience requires attention. Participant  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>9 pointed out that their experience has shown that brands tends to lose considerable value when consumers take action from influencers posts because </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>online for the brand and / or its products / promotions and not readily find the  information. They could click on links that go to websites that are not user friendly  or mobile optimised, and be poorly designed – or at worst, not work at all. They  may enter promotional codes on checkout that don’t work, or have to go through  cumbersome registration processes and provide unnecessary amounts of  information. Making the online experience seamless, enjoyable, user friendly,  and quick is seen a complementor to deriving value from DIM. Marketers also </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>need to improve their ability to understand how to track and measure DIM activity,  and Digital funnel performance.   The access to, training, and use of influencer marketing technology has also been </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>highlighted as a key enabler that helps marketers make influencer marketing  “simpler, safer, and ultimately more predictable” (Participant 10). These  technologies cover influencer analysis and selection, content publishing, social  media, and engagement reporting to name a few. Businesses are faced with age  old choices as to whether to build or buy these technologies.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Brand, Media). Yet others expressed that it is most likely better outsourced to  agency partners who remain best equipped to deal with the complexities. What  emerged from the research however is that organisations who opt to develop </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>separate internal core competencies in influencer marketing are typically early  adopters who have a relatively mature and entrenched brand, and whose brands  and products success are premised on them being and remaining relevant in </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>popular culture. They also tend to need to execute marketing relatively quickly in order to remain relevant and capture share of voice. Others are happy to develop </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>together with supporting frameworks and guidelines for their various marketing  teams, and theirs partners and agencies. In this instance, Influencer marketing is  not necessarily located within a specific marketing function, but a cross functional  capability with the different areas that contribute to the overall DIM strategy, and  the execution of campaigns. This model is largely adopted by organisations with  multiple business units, product categories, and marketing departments. Their  main needs are to enhance their brand and marketing through using influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing both as a media channel, and as a strategic marketing capability.    Key features identified in the organisations that choose to outsource DIM entirely </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>are that their business model focus remains on their core business proposition,  such as quick service restaurants or retailing. Marketing within these type </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>organisations serve to enable their commercial objectives and business targets  more directly.   A move away from functional siloes towards cross-functional marketing teams </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>such as agile marketing squads based on the marketing objectives and target  markets  is envisaged by many as an enabler of effective DIM. More education  for marketers in the areas of Influencer Briefing, Influencer Tools, Influencer </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Engagement, Social Media Marketing, Messaging Penetration Measurement,  Influencer Agreements, and Influencer Analytics has been identified from the  research. Irrespective of the model chosen, the research pointed out that  marketers within organisations ought to be knowledgeable in, and au fair with </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>DIM practices. Also, the capability to finding influencers is ideally suited to  external partners who contribute actively to the creative industries, and who move  around and participate in creative circles. Strategically however, particularly for </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>larger type organisations with multiple brands and products, the consensus is that  a seperate Influencer strategist type role would be beneficial within them, this  would help organisations to develop an overarching strategy for DIM. It would  also enable them to share learnings and best practices internally amongst </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>different marketing departments, and would support the development of standards for measurement and performance. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>owned, and earned marketing. In some cases, DIM campaigns may involve all  marketing functions and channels – particularly when “above the line” media is  being used, and in other instances, it may only require PR where for example  unpaid influencers are invited to offline events. In the case of Social Media, online  organic Share of Voice (SOV) is earned via Influencer content, thus DIM supports  marketing activity across paid, owned and earned marketing touchpoints in all  marketing stages i.e. Awareness, Consideration, Purchase, Service, and Loyalty. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>within marketing stages  Participant 4 observed that for successful DIM campaigns, clear lines of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>accountability and assigned roles and responsibilities are needed. In their  experience, organisations do not yet have a process for DIM, and since DIM  touches on so many marketing functions, this leads to a relatively uncoordinated  effort from marketers involved. Furthermore, the fact that Influencers can add </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>value in both the physical and digital worlds necessitates an omnichannel marketing approach from the onset. Marketers would do well to consider how </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Another often overlooked and very important consideration when using  Influencers is the “Influencer Experience” with the brand, the company, and the  campaign (Participants 1, 2, 9,13,14, 17). Things such as the manner in which  they are treated, consistently fair and on-time payment, quality and timeous  briefing, and clear 2 way communication are all aspects for marketers to ensure  when conducting DIM. Poor management of these components could lead to  unintended consequences with negative sentiment spilling over into Social </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>media. Influencer collaboration skills that appreciate the always-on nature of the  engagement and communication with busy influencers are also deemed critical.  Whether internally located or outsourced, sensitivity towards the human side of  working with influencers is also necessary, as is understanding and appreciating </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>their communication and professional style, tastes, and personality. The  Influencer experience with the brand also plays a role in retaining influencers for  whom several brands are competing (Participant 14).   Marketers should also be aware that as much as they want Influencers to be </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>invested in their companies brand, Influencers also have their own brand to build  and manage. Bi-directional investment in each others brands is therefore </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>advised, particularly for the more professional, well-known, and high engagement  influencers.   Whilst the brand and marketing perspectives in terms of capabilities and enablers </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>for DIM has been discussed, little has been said about these in relation to the  influencers themselves. Although out of the scope of this research, some  participants identified gaps with influencers (Participants 2, 5, 9, 17). They  propose Influencer programs to help them work more effectively with brands. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Aspects such as training in managing their own brand as influencers, marketing  copywriting expertise, design skills, multimedia content production capabilities,  commercial negotiation ability,  client service knowledge, reporting cadence and  quality, and general business management skills were highlighted as key </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>enablers. Influencers are also expected to work on multiple projects and priorities in an agile manner, therefore, skills and training to help them manage and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Given that DIM cuts across functions, to support organisations to develop and  execute on Influencer marketing strategies and campaigns, an “Influencer  marketing panel” made up of senior personnel from the different marketing  functions is recommended. This would ensure the necessary integration and  collaboration structure are in place.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>enabled, cross-functional, and real-time modern marketing management  practices to be successful. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>The research indicated a strong move towards agile marketing practices to  leverage the tactical opportunities that DIM presents. It also emphasised the use  of data for performance measurement and monitoring, as well as the ability to  test, learn and optimise marketing in real-time. The cross-functional nature of DIM  was highlighted throughout the research, making it a key success factor in  executing on DIM campaigns. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>understanding amongst the various participants. The research indicated several categories of risk, these are  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>example bot accounts, which overstate their actual reach and  engagement.   • Brand Reputation Risk: Where harm is caused to the brands image, due </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to their association with the influencer, or through some action or inaction  by them, whether intentional or not.  • Commercial Risks: Where the brand stands to lose money or get poor </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>results or ROI as a results of campaign non-performance, poor  engagement rates, or overpriced services.   • Delivery Risk: Where Influencers do not fulfil on their obligations to attend  events, produce or publish content, or participate in agreed brand  activities.   Expert research participants tended to concur that the main aspect to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>mitigating most risks are 1) upfront research and analysis of influencers, 2)  close collaboration to align interest and values between the brand and  influencers, 3) developing clear content and activity schedules, 4) assigning </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>clear roles and responsibilities, and 5) developing and negotiating contracts.    By far, “Brand Reputation” was the most cited risk concern amongst </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>participants, with a considerable number of factors leading to it such as “brand  noise” (Participants 1, 4, 7, 13). An important consideration is the number and  type of brands an influencer represents.   strategies as established via the research </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>engagement and communication sessions. A brand manager in the FMCG  industry that was interviewed said that apart from formal “Brand Induction” for  influencers, his company has weekly informal “get togethers” in a fun and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>social setting at their premises with an open invitation for their brand partners,  suppliers, and   agencies – including influencers. This allows them to connect  with their influencers regularly, and to engage them on any pertinent issues  and opportunities. Whilst not specifically focused on managing risk, this does  help them to identify, understand, and resolve any looming disputes  (Participant 12). A recommendation therefore to mitigate this type of risk  would be for marketers to regularly engage with influencers representing their </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>brand, informally and socially, in order to proactively address possible brand  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>damage arising from disagreements. More formal approaches such as “Brand Influencer Councils” have also been touted as ways of minimising brand </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>structure that offers things like brand training, product knowledge, and  coaching and support for select influencers with high brand affinity.  Fundamentally, many marketers concur that influencers should be seen as an  extension of the brand and the companies workforce. They ought to be treated  with the same level of care that an organisation might treat their employees  with, and that this should be nurtured by developing meaningful long term  relationships with them.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>A common approach taken by many marketers as Participant 9 pointed out is  to first decide on the role that the infuencer is expected to play in the  campaign. 3 discrete type roles were identified i.e. Supporting, Integrated, and  Lead roles. Supporting roles generally limit the use of influencers as an “add-</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>on” to a marketing initiative. Influencers receive a brief to post a certain type  of communication that supports a promotion or event, or to generate talkability  for something the brand and company is doing. There is little integration of  the influencer across marketing functions and activities, and they are not part  of the overall brand marketing and campaign strategies. In integrated roles  however, Influencers are central to all activities. They participate in the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>research, strategy formulation, and design and execution of all marketing  activities – be that ATL such as TV, Radio, Outdoor etc, or BTL such  sponsorships events, product launches, and customer experience activities.  They also work across all marketing functions and contribute to the Digital, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>PR, and Media strategies and channel planning. Finally, in Influence-led  approaches, the main thrust of the creative framework, messaging and  content themes, and brand strategies are built around influencers. Marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>strategies, advertising activities, and media channels feature influencers  prominently.   In supporting roles, the impact of Influencer risk such as brand reputation, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>audience fraud etc is low. However, in integrated and influencer led  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>approaches, these become higher given the close association with the brand. Therefore, each of these approaches require a different level of risk </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>management, legal and other mechanisms as Influencers become more  embedded in brand marketing activities.   It is also advisable for brands to have a “crisis communication” management </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>plan catering for Influencers. This should includes things like holding  statements in the event an influencer “goes rogue”, and actions such as  immediate pausing of campaign activity in the event of an issue arising. Also,  disassociating with an influencer and processes for executing a “take down” </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>notice for offending content may be necessary depending on the nature of the  issue. As digital is immediate in nature, delays in communication could  exacerbate brand damage. Maintaining shorter and more frequent cycle of  communications on Digital channels with regular updates is seen to be an </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>effective measure to reduce brand reputational damage (Participants 8,9,16).   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>community rules and ethics, with built in recourse for those offended to report  offensive behaviour or content. Reported content is reviewed and the  offending user is suspended and the content is taken down.  Another avenue  specific to South Africa are the consumer protection bodies such as the ARB </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(Advertising Regulatory Body), or National Broadcasting complaints  Commision (NABSA). These govern fake or malicious advertising to  consumers, and to whom consumers can direct their complaints. The Internet </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Advertising Bureau (IABSA) has recently put in place an Influencer Marketing  Committee that aims to develop best practices related to Digital Influencer  Marketing. An area receiving considerable attention is the need for disclosure </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>of collaboration with brands by Influencers through specifying that the Influencer is being paid by the brand for content. There are proponents for </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>apply to all types of brand / influencer arrangements. Those for it emphasise  the need for consistency and transparency in the interest of consumer  protection and to ensure the same standards for all DIM campaigns. Apart  from this, there appears to be no unified standards or regulation that govern  DIM. With that said, the research indicated that upfront discussions and  negotiations resulting in formal contractual agreement between the brand and  influencers are seen as one of the most important tools to govern the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>relationship, as well as to mitigation risks.   What is also helpful is to arm influencers with “Frequently Asked Questions” </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>(FAQ) guides related to the product or service being promoted, as well as  company contact details to whom enquiries from consumers can be directed. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Participant 3 suggested a complementary guide of “do’s and don’t’s” as well  which can include aspects such as contentious topics not to engage on. An  example cited by a beverage brand that participated in the research was  detailed information to influencers on questions and engagements related to  sugar tax. Participant 4 highlighted this aspect as well with a case studying  citing a male influencer who prepared dinner for his family, including a baby, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>using ready-made dinner products that were perceived to be not suitable for  infants. Some consumers took offense to the content shared, calling on the  brand to desist from promoting their products as suitable for infants. These  suggested mechanisms are seen as tools that help to empower influencers to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>engage and communicate effectively and authentically with their audiences.  In this manner, they can also remain compliant with brand or industry  standards and regulations.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>In order to manage and improve influencer compliance and risk, a trend towards developing more stringent legal contracts to govern brand-</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Whilst the research uncovered differences in opinion around managing risk  and compliance, the need for specific and detailed Influencer agreements was  identified, and is expected to occur.  Some participants believed that the best  risk mitigation strategy ought to be better briefing, deeper relationships,  improved communication, and regular engagements with Influencers. This  they argued would reduce the chances of something going wrong. Others  believed that many risks can be avoided by better Influencer selection upfront. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Some preferred to transfer risks by using Influencer platform providers to  mediate the selection, management and payment of influencers. Whatever  their differences however, all participants indicated the requirement to having  a clear, detailed, and binding contract in place with influencers. This should at </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>minimum cover deliverables, schedule, content rights, payment, and dispute  processes.   Interestingly, whilst contracts are seen as internal mechanisms to manage </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>risk, there is little in the form of external recourse for companies. With the  exception of the few industry leading participants who participated in the  research, marketers themselves expect that other parties will drive and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>develop the necessary policies, regulations, and governance standards.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing functions. Chief amongst these are   • Social Media Marketing which provides effective tactical marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>capabilities for DIM engagement, organic reach, and content sharing to  online communities. Online reputation management, community </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>management, and building online brand communities are key capabilities from Social Media that are used for DIM. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>to which DIM can be compared such as cost per reach, cost per  impression, advertising frequency benchmarks, and target market  penetration rates. This allows marketers to understand the media benefits </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and efficiencies of using influencers as and advertising channel.   • Digital Performance Marketing provides the ability to track results and  conversions, notably for marketing sales promotion activity through DIM. </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This is done via Click through rate, Cost per Click, Cost Per Lead, and  Cost Per Acquisition metrics. Collectively, these enable ROMI and ROI  tracking for digital business and e-commerce channels.    • Public Relations Management enables marketers to produce high Share  of Voice, Positive Sentiment, Talkability, and Contexual Relevance when  executing DIM campaigns. It also provides DIM with crisis communications </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>frameworks to protect brand image and reputation.    • Cultural Marketing supports marketers to achieve brand immersion,  hyper-segmentation, and niche audience insights when using DIM. It also </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>allows brands to make a meaningful contribution to customers, and their  culture through the embedded nature of DIM initiatives within online  communities and tribes in a relevant and value adding manner.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Brand Marketing offers marketers the brand guardrails from which DIM  executes on – and aligns to. This can include the organisations Brand  Strategy, its Brand Values, the Brand CI, and its Brand Ambassadors. It </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>prioritises the need to protect Brand Reputation, and encourages strong  Brand Loyalty, positive Brand Experiences, and Brand Fit.  • Event Marketing  gives marketers the framework for the physical  components of managing Influencers who represent the brand at </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>sponsored, branded, or partner events.  Event briefing and content guides,  managing ambassador appearances, and developing and marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>curated experiences have clear parallels to influencer marketing.   </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Marketing Research &amp; Insights supports marketers who conduct DIM with market and industry data, consumer insights, customer behavioural </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>social media, influencer, and advertising platforms informs DIM strategies  to make them highly effective.   There therefore is a symbiotic relationship between DIM and other forms of </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>marketing, with DIM used to support different types of activities and vica versa.  What is key to successful execution is cross-functional integration, and clear roles </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>and responsibilities amongst marketers involved in DIM strategies and  campaigns.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
    </chapterFour>
    <chapterFive>
      <paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>CHAPTER 5. CONCLUSIONS &amp; RECOMMENDATIONS</textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>This research report has discussed at length the best practices related to DIM  execution and management. At an industry and strategy level, there are multiple  recommendations that emanate out of this research, these are  • A Unified Measurement Standard for DIM, similar to the “Barcelona </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>Principles” agreed upon by the PR industry, which sets standards at a  global level for PR measurement. This could be an integrated standard </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>with input from all marketing disciplines    • Common and agreed upon DIM industry toolkit that could contain  sample influencer selection checklists, risk plans, reputational tools, </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencer contract templates etc. This will support practitioners to  uniformly plan, manage, and execute DIM campaigns.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Brand specific DIM Playbooks developed by organisations and their partners to provide guidelines to marketers on how to go about doing DIM </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>product and marketing environment is unique, these context specific will  enable organisations to align best practices internally.   • Training and Certification for both Influencer and Marketers on the </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>various DIM areas eg. Selection, Payment, Risk etc. This will allow them  to gain the requisite DIM knowledge and expertise through formal means  rather than through experience alone. Higher education institutes and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>professional bodies could add this into marketing curricula.   • Influencer Coaching and Training on managing their own brand, as  well as on managing themselves and their clients as a business. This </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>would enable smoother interaction on commercial, legal, financial, project  delivery, content production and other matters.  • Influencer Code of Conduct as a voluntary code subscribed to by all </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>influencers that work commercially with organisations. This will support  accountability from influencers on their online content and behaviour, as  well as allow them to share best practices amongst themselves.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>• Influencer Industry Specific accreditation, such as pharmaceutical,  financial, alcohol, retail etc. This could be in the form of a “badge” or </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>“trustmark” that verifies that they have training or experience in an  industries specific marketing nuisances and regulations. This will help  brands identify Influencers that have experience in regulated industries, or  with specific type of customers.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>different views were assimilated into the research to present an objective and  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>balanced perspective, there were very diverse views on best practices within certain areas from the different participants, in some cases conflicting with </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>perspective would deepen marketers understanding of related DIM best practices  within different marketing discplines.   Also the company types in the representative sample was varied, with marketing </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>operations and process best practices being widely different depending on  whether the participant represented a creative agency, a platform, a brand, or a  specialist agency.  The industry ecosystem is still being shaped with each area  jostling to ensure that there is minimal disruption to their current business models </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>whilst still embracing and preparing for change. There appear to be concerns of  being disintermediated by many of the participants. Research around an industry  operating model and ecosystem would benefit the participants and support them  to move forward.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>There are also nuances specific to different industries in terms of their general  and specific advertising regulations and limitations. These are not readily  transferable or understood in digital advertising and marketing environments,  such as influencer marketing. As an example, Alcohol advertising is prohibited to  under 18’s in South Africa, how do these brands then verify that an Influencers  audience do not include this market? Industry specific research that seeks to </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>understand its regulations and limitations as it relates to Digital Environments will  help marketers to more readily apply them in a DIM context.   Finally, none of the corporate /‘participants had considered any form of formal </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>skills development, training, or organisational development work for DIM.  Research into organisational structure, change management, and training and  skills development as it relates to DIM could be undertaken to bolster marketing  capabilities within organisation. This is more important for organisation types that </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>provide favourable environments for building internal DIM environments.   It should be noted that the study has been conducted in South Africa, and </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>although many of the best practices contained herein can be generalisable  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
        <Paragraph>
          <textChunk>globally, it is unclear at what stage of development marketers in other countries may be in terms of DIM.  </textChunk>
        </Paragraph>
      </paragraph>
    </chapterFive>
  </contentSection>
  <appendixSection>
    <Appendices>
      <listOfFigures>
        <string>APPENDIX A – Participant  Information Sheet</string>
        <string>Attention: [Insert addressee details], [Contact person], [Organisation name]  Dear [Name]  Re: Request for your participation in Qualitative Research Interview on Influencer  Marketing in SA  My name is Ahmed Kajee, I am a Chartered Marketer South Africa (CMSA) presently working as  the Head of Digital Marketing and Social Media at Nedbank. I am currently completing an  academic research thesis as part of a Master of Management in Digital Business degree at the  University of Witwatersrand’s (WITS). My supervisor is Laurence Beder, Adjunct lecturer at WITS  Business School. </string>
        <string>As part of this project, I would like to invite you to take part in an interview. The research is titled  “Management Practices for Digital Influencer Marketing” which seeks to better understand  the growing field of Influencer Marketing in the context of South Africa, from a marketing </string>
        <string>management point of view. I would like to conduct remote interviews via MS Teams with  experienced marketing practitioners who have had exposure to influencer marketing campaigns </string>
        <string>in any capacity over the preceding 12 months.   Amongst the best practices we are researching when using Influencer marketing are aspects such </string>
        <string>as Influencer Selection Methodologies, Brand Reputation and Safety Management, Influencer  Fraud and Risk Factors, Payment Models and Fees, Campaign Tracking, Measurement, Process  and Management, Creative Control, and Influencer Ethics and Disclosure. As the research aims </string>
        <string>to understand this area better from marketing experts working in the field, input on best practices  in other areas will be welcomed. The interview will therefore consist of several open-ended </string>
        <string>guiding questions, and be conducted in a semi-structured manner to allow for dialogue on any  salient points that we could discuss further. This activity will take between 60 - 90 minutes. With </string>
        <string>your permission, I would also like to record the interview.   There will be no personal costs to you if you participate in this project, you will not receive any  direct benefits from participation but there are no disadvantages or penalties if you do not choose </string>
        <string>to participate or if you withdraw from the study. You may withdraw at any time or not answer any  question if you do not want to. The interview will be completely confidential and the information </string>
        <string>you give to me will be held securely on a password protected device and not disclosed to anyone  else. I will be using a pseudonym (false name) to represent your participation in my final research </string>
        <string>report.   If you have any questions during or afterwards about this research, feel free to contact me on the  details listed below. This study will be written up as a research report, I will be pleased to send </string>
        <string>the summary to you and would welcome an opportunity to share its insights with you in a  telephonic discussion. The data collected from this research project will be stored securely and </string>
        <string>will be kept for 1 years. If you have any concerns or complaints regarding the ethical procedures  of this study, you are welcome to contact the University Human Research Ethics Committee (Non-</string>
        <string>Medical), telephone +27(0) 11 717 1408, email hrec-medical.researchoffice@wits.ac.za.   If you require further information regarding this research, please contact me on ahmed@kajee.org </string>
        <string>or via mobile on 082 4900 290, or my supervisor Laurence Beder on laurence.beder@wits.ac.za  Yours sincerely,  </string>
        <string>Mr. Ahmed Kajee   Master of Business Administration (UCT) </string>
        <string>PgDip Honours, KISM (Stellenbosch)   Chartered Marketer, CMSA (MASA) </string>
        <string>APPENDIX B – Interview Guide Qualitative Semi-Structured Interview Guide </string>
        <string>1.</string>
        <string>IMGD Influencer Marketing Growth  IMC Strategies?   and Development </string>
        <string>2.</string>
        <string>IMC strategies?  </string>
        <string>3.</string>
        <string>you developing them?  </string>
        <string>4.</string>
        <string>IMPP Influencer Marketing  and measured?  Performance &amp; Payment </string>
        <string>5.</string>
        <string>influencers?  and Guidelines  </string>
        <string>8.</string>
        <string>9.</string>
        <string>influencer marketing?   Capabilities and Enablers  </string>
        <string>12.</string>
        <string>compliance factors when using influencers?  Management  </string>
        <string>14.</string>
        <string>DIM best practices?  </string>
        <string>APPENDIX C – Participant  Consent Form Research Topic: Management Practices for Digital Influencer Marketing Management </string>
        <string>Name of researcher: Ahmed Kajee, WITS MMDB 2020, Student No: 1010743  I, ……………………………………….., agree to participate as an interviewee for this  research project. The research has been explained to me and I understand what my  participation will involve. I agree to the following:  (Please circle the relevant options below). </string>
        <string>I agree that my participation will remain anonymous       YES NO  I agree that the researcher may use anonymous quotes in his /       YES NO </string>
        <string>her research report  I agree that the interview may be audio recorded       YES NO  Interviewee </string>
        <string>…………………………………… (signature)  …………………………………… (name of participant)  …………………………………… (date)  Researcher  …………………………………… (signature)  Ahmed Kajee…………………… (name of person seeking consent)  …………………………………… (date)  Kindly complete and sign this form and return via email to ahmed@kajee.org </string>
        <string>APPENDIX D – Influencer Rate Card Example </string>
      </listOfFigures>
    </Appendices>
  </appendixSection>
  <referenceSection>
    <referencePage>
      <listOfReferences>
        <string>REFERENCES ............................................................................ 128</string>
        <string>APPENDIX A – Participant  Information Sheet ......................... 132  APPENDIX B – Interview Guide ................................................. 133 </string>
        <string>APPENDIX C – Participant  Consent Form ............................... 134  APPENDIX D – Influencer Rate Card Example ......................... 135  APPENDIX E – Influencer Audience Data Example ................. 136 </string>
        <string>ix  REFERENCES  Appel, G., Grewal, L., Hadi, R., &amp; Stephen, A.T. (2019). The future of social media </string>
        <string>in marketing. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science 48:79–95  Armstrong, S., Esber, D., Heller, J., &amp; Timelin, B. (2020).  Modern marketing: </string>
        <string>What it is, what it isn’t, and how to do it. McKinsey &amp; Company,  Brown, D., &amp; Fiorella, S. (2013). Influence Marketing: How to Create, Manage, </string>
        <string>and Measure Brand Influencers in Social Media Marketing. Indianapolis, in: Que  Publishing.  Boerman, S.C., Willemsen, L. M., &amp; Van Der Aa, E. P. (2017).“This Post Is </string>
        <string>Sponsored” Effects of Sponsorship Disclosure on Persuasion Knowledge and  Electronic Word of Mouth in the Context of Facebook. Journal of Interactive  Marketing 38, 82–92  Bryman, A., &amp; Bell, E. (2007) “Business Research Methods”, 2nd edition. Oxford </string>
        <string>University Press   Bizcommunity (2020). Ogilvy launches new influencer marketing tool in SA. </string>
        <string>Retrieved from https://www.bizcommunity.com/InBrief/196/11/15587.html   Campbell, C., &amp; Farrel, J. R. (2020). More than meets the eye: The functional </string>
        <string>components underlying influencer marketing, 2020 Kelley School of Business,  Indiana University. Published by Elsevier Inc.   Campbell, S. (2014). What is qualitative research?. Clinical Laboratory Science, </string>
        <string>27(1), 3.  Chen, Z., &amp; Yuan, M. (2020). Psychology of word of mouth marketing, </string>
        <string>ScienceDirect, Current Opinion in Psychology 31:7–10  Cooper, D.R., &amp; Schindler, P.S. (2006). Business Research Methods (Ninth </string>
        <string>Edition, International Edition). McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.  Creswell, J. W. (2013). Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed </string>
        <string>methods approaches. Sage publications.  Crotty, M. (1998). The foundations of social research: Meaning and perspective </string>
        <string>in the research process. Sage publications.  Creswell, J. W., Hanson, W. E., Plano, C., &amp; Morales, A. (2007). Qualitative </string>
        <string>research designs: Selection and implementation. The counseling psychologist,  35(2), 236-264.  Creswell, J. W., &amp; Creswell, J. D. (2018). Research Design: Qualitative, </string>
        <string>Quantitative, and Mixed Methods Approaches. Sage Publications. 5th Edition.  </string>
        <string>Dmock, T (2019). The Digital Transformation of the Marketing Department, Capgemini Invest, Praxis Transfer 02/2019, 38-43 </string>
        <string>affects customer opinion and helps or damages brands. International Hellenic  University  Erdogan, B. Z. (1999), “Celebrity endorsement: a literature review”, Journal of </string>
        <string>Marketing Management, Vol. 15 No. 4, pp. 291-314.  Flanagin, A.J., &amp; Metzger, M.J. (2007), “The role of site features, user attributes, </string>
        <string>and information verification behaviors on the perceived credibility of web-based  information”, New Media &amp; Society, Vol. 9 No. 2, pp. 319-342.  Gross, J., &amp; von Wangenheim, F. (2018). The big four of Influencer Marketing. </string>
        <string>ETH Zurich, Switzerland, Chair of Technology Marketing. Marketing Review St.  Gallen 2018.   Hughes, C., Swaminathan, V., &amp; Brooks, G (2019). Driving Brand Engagement </string>
        <string>Through Online Social Influencers: An Empirical Investigation of Sponsored  Blogging Campaigns. Journal of Marketing 2019, Vol. 83(5) 78-96, American  Marketing Association 2019  Hwang, Y., &amp; Jeong, SH. (2016). “This is a sponsored blog post, but all opinions </string>
        <string>are my own”: The effects of sponsorship disclosure on responses to sponsored  blog posts. Computers in Human Behavior, Volume 62, September 2016, Pages  </string>
        <string>phenomenon creating a new frontier of virtual opportunities. Faculty of  Economics and Management Slovak University of Agriculture. Communication  Today. Article · January 2018  Keller, K. L. (2016). Unlocking the Power of Integrated Marketing </string>
        <string>Communications: How Integrated Is Your IMC Program?, Journal of Advertising,  </string>
        <string>Kemp, S.  (2020a). Digital 2020: South Africa. February 2020, We Are Social and  HootSuite. DataReportal </string>
        <string>HootSuite. DataReportal  Komok, A. (2020). What is AQS (Audience Quality Score) and how is it </string>
        <string>calculated? Retrieved from https://help.hypeauditor.com/en/articles/2221731- what-is-aqs-audience-quality-score-and-how-is-it-calculated  Kostic, S.C., &amp; Okanovic, M. (2018). Influencer Marketing in a Social Media </string>
        <string>Context. Symorg, 2018. University of Belgrade.   Kotler, P., Kartajaya, H., &amp; Setiawan, I. (2017). Marketing 4.0: Moving from </string>
        <string>Traditional to Digital. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.,   McCracken, G. (1989), “Who is the celebrity endorser? Cultural foundations of </string>
        <string>the endorsement process”, Journal of Consumer Research, Vol. 16 No. 3, pp.  </string>
        <string>qualitative inquiry. Qualitative Health Research, 25(9), 1212-1222.  Nirschl M., &amp; Steinberg L. 2018. Einstieg in das Influencer Marketing. Springer </string>
        <string>Gabler.  Neuman, W. L. (2009). Social research methods: Qualitative and quantitative </string>
        <string>approaches (7th ed.). Boston: Allyn &amp; Bacon.  O’Brien, D., Main, A., Kounkel, S., &amp; Stephen, A. R. (2019). 2020 Global </string>
        <string>Marketing Trends: Bringing authenticity to our digital age. Deloitte Insights,  Copyright © 2019 Deloitte Development LLC.   Park, D. H., Lee, J., &amp; Han, I. (2007). The effect of on-line consumer reviews on </string>
        <string>consumer purchasing intention: The moderating role of involvement. International  journal of electronic commerce,11(4), 125-148.  Paton, M. (2002). Qualitatative Research and Evaluation Methods. Sage </string>
        <string>Publications  Rakuten (2019). Influencer Marketing Report, Rakuten Marketing  </string>
        <string>Rosario, A. B., De Valck, K., &amp; Sotgiu, F. (2020). Conceptualizing the electronic  word-of-mouth process: What we know and need to know about eWOM creation,  exposure, and evaluation. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science 48:422– </string>
        <string>Saunders, M., &amp; Lewis, P. Thornhill, A. (2012) “Research Methods for Business  Students” 6th edition, Pearson Education Limited. </string>
        <string>Media on Sales: A Study of a Microlending Marketplace,” Journal of Marketing  Research, 49 (5), 624–39.  Stokes, R. (2018). eMarketing, The essential guide to marketing in a digital world, </string>
        <string>6th Edition. Published in 2018 by The Red &amp; Yellow Creative School of Business  Stubb, C., Nyström, A.G., &amp; Colliander, J. (2019), "Influencer marketing: The </string>
        <string>impact of disclosing sponsorship compensation justification on sponsored  content effectiveness", Journal of Communication Management, Vol. 23 No. 2,  pp. 109-122 </string>
        <string>Talkwater (2019). The Global State of Influencer Marketing in 2019. Copyright,  Talkwater, 2019.   Titus, P. A. (2007). Applied Creativity: The Creative Marketing Breakthrough </string>
        <string>Model. December 2007. Journal of Marketing Education 29(3):262-272  YPulse (2020). Cancel Culture: An Explainer for Brands. Retrieved from </string>
        <string>https://www.ypulse.com/article/2020/07/09/cancel-culture-an-explainer-for- brands/   </string>
      </listOfReferences>
    </referencePage>
  </referenceSection>
</ProposalDocument>